<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Educader</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">Main2Activity</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main3">Main3Activity</string>


    common first year
    <string name="electrical">BASIC ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING</string>
    <string name="math">ENGINEERING MATHMATICS-1</string>
    <string name="chemistry">ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY</string>
    <string name="program">PROGRAMMING FOR PROBLEM SOLVING</string>
    <string name="graphics">ENGINEERING GRAPHICS AND DESIGN</string>
    <string name="physics">ENGINEERING PHYSICS</string>
    <string name="math2">ENGINEERING MATHMATICS-2</string>
    <string name="english">PROFESSIONAL ENGLISH</string>

    cs second year
    <string name="SOFTWARE">SOFTWARE ENGINEERING</string>
    <string name="DATASTRC">DATA STRUCTURE</string>
    <string name="MICRO">INTRODUCTION TO MICROPROCESSOR</string>
    <string name="DLD">DIGITAL LOGIC DESIGN</string>
    <string name="TUFFEL">THEORY OF AUTOMETA AND FORMAL LANGUAGES</string>
    <string name="DISCRETE">DISCRETE STRUCTURE AND THEORY OF LOGIC </string>
    <string name="OS">OPERATING SYSTEM</string>
    <string name="MATHS3">MATHS 3</string>
    <string name="HUMANVALUE">UNIVERSAL HUMAN VALUES</string>
    <string name="COA">COMPUTER ORGANIZATION AND ARCHITECTURE</string>


    cs third year
    <string name="PPL">PRINCIPAL OF PROGRAMING LANGUAGE</string>
    <string name="GRAPHICS">COMPUTER GRAPHICS</string>
    <string name="NETWORK">COMPUTER NETWORKS</string>
    <string name="WT">WEB TECHNOLOGY</string>
    <string name="INDUSTRIAL">INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT</string>
    <string name="CYBER">CYBER SECURITY</string>
    <string name="DBMS">DATABASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM</string>
    <string name="ECONOMICS">MANAGERIAL ECONOMICS</string>
    <string name="COMPILER">COMPILER DESIGN</string>
    <string name="SOCIOLOGY">INDUSTRIAL SOCIOLOGY</string>
    <string name="DAA">DESIGN AND ANALYSIS OF ALGORITHMS</string>
    <string name="DATAMINING">DATA WAREHOUSING AND DATA MINING</string>


    ME second year
    <string name="SCIENCE_ME"> ENGINEERING SCIENCE COURSE</string>
    <string name="MATH_3_ME">MATH-3</string>
    <string name="TECHINAL_ME">TECHNICAL COMMUNICATION </string>
    <string name="HUMAN_ME">UNIVERSAL HUMAN VALUES</string>
    <string name="THERMO">THERMODYNAMICS</string>
    <string name="FLUID">FLUID MECHANICS AND FLUID MACHINES </string>
    <string name="MATERIALS">MATERIALS ENGINEERING</string>
    <string name="APPLIED">APPLIED THERMODYNAMICS</string>
    <string name="MECHANICS">ENGINEERING MECHANICS</string>
    <string name="MANUFAC">MANUFACTURING PROCESSES</string>


    ME third year
    <string name="MACHINE">MACHINE DESIGN-1</string>
    <string name="HEAT">HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER</string>
    <string name="MANUFACTURING_2">MANUFACTURING SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY-2</string>
    <string name="IC">IC ENGINES AND COMPRESSORS</string>
    <string name="INDUSTRIAL_ME">INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT</string>
    <string name="CYBER_ME">CYBER SECURITY</string>
    <string name="F_MACHINES"> FLUID MACHINERY</string>
    <string name="ECONOMICS_ME">MANAGERIAL ECONOMICS</string>
    <string name="MACHINE_DESIGN">MACHINE DESIGN-2</string>
    <string name="SOCIOLOGY_ME">SOCIOLOGY</string>
    <string name="THEORY">THEORY OF MACHINES</string>
    <string name="RELIABILITY">RELIABILITY ENGINEERING </string>


    EE second year
    <string name="SCIENCE"> ENGINEERING SCIENCE COURSE</string>
    <string name="MATH_3">MATH-3</string>
    <string name="TECHINAL">TECHNICAL COMMUNICATION </string>
    <string name="HUMAN">UNIVERSAL HUMAN VALUES</string>
    <string name="ELECTRICAL">ELECTRICAL MEASUREMENTS AND INSTRUMENTATION</string>
    <string name="ELECTROMAGNETIC">ELECTROMAGNETIC FIELD THEORY </string>
    <string name="ELECTRONICS">DIGITAL ELECTRONICS</string>
    <string name="MECHINES">ELECTRICAL MECHINES-1</string>
    <string name="ANALYSAS">NETWORKS ANALYSIS AND SYNTHESIS</string>
    <string name="SIGNALS">BASIC SIGNALS AND SYSTEMS</string>


    EE third year
    <string name="MECHINES_2">ELECTRICAL MECHINES-2</string>
    <string name="PTAD">POWER TRANSMISSION AND DISTIBUTION</string>
    <string name="CONTROL">CONTROL SYSTEM</string>
    <string name="PSO">POWER SYSTEM OPTIMIZATION</string>
    <string name="INDUSTRIAL_EE">INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT</string>
    <string name="CYBER_EE">CYBER SECURITY</string>
    <string name="PE">POWER ELECTRONICS</string>
    <string name="ECONOMICS_EE">MANAGERIAL ECONOMICS</string>
    <string name="MICROPRO">MICROPROCESSOR</string>
    <string name="SOCIOLOGY_EE"> SOCIOLOGY</string>
    <string name="PSA">POWER SYSTEM ANALYSIS</string>
    <string name="VOLTAGE">HIGH VOLTAGE ENGINEERING</string>


    ECE second year
    <string name="SCIENCE_ECE"> ENGINEERING SCIENCE COURSE</string>
    <string name="MATH_3_ECE">MATH-3</string>
    <string name="TECHINAL_ECE">TECHNICAL COMMUNICATION </string>
    <string name="HUMAN_ECE">UNIVERSAL HUMAN VALUES</string>
    <string name="DSD">DIGITAL SYSTEM DESIGN</string>
    <string name="COMM_ENG">COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING </string>
    <string name="ELECTRONICS_ECE">ELECTRONICS DEVICES</string>
    <string name="CIRCUIT">ANALOG CIRCUITS</string>
    <string name="ANALYSAS_ECE">NETWORKS ANALYSIS AND SYNTHESIS</string>
    <string name="SIGNAL_ECE"> SIGNAL SYSTEMS</string>


    ECE third year
    <string name="POC">PRINCIPALS OF COMMUNICATIONS</string>
    <string name="INTEGRATED">INTEGRATED CIRCUITS</string>
    <string name="DSP">DIGITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING</string>
    <string name="AWP">ANTENNA AND WAVE PROPAGATION</string>
    <string name="INDUSTRIAL_ECE">INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT</string>
    <string name="CYBER_ECE">CYBER SECURITY</string>
    <string name="SYSTEM_1">CONTROL SYSTEM-1</string>
    <string name="ECONOMICS_ECE">MANAGERIAL ECONOMICS</string>
    <string name="MICROWAVE">MICROWAVE ENGINEERING</string>
    <string name="SOCIOLOGY_ECE">INDUSTRIAL SOCIOLOGY</string>
    <string name="DC">DIGITAL COMMUNICATION</string>
    <string name="ASP">ANALOG SIGNAL PROCESSING</string>


    CIVIL second year
    <string name="SCIENCE_CIV"> ENGINEERING SCIENCE COURSE</string>
    <string name="MATH_3_CIV">MATH-3</string>
    <string name="TECHINAL_CIV">TECHNICAL COMMUNICATION </string>
    <string name="HUMAN_CIV">UNIVERSAL HUMAN VALUES</string>
    <string name="FLUID_CIV">FLUID MECHANICS </string>
    <string name="MECHANICS_CIV">ENGINEERING MECHANICS</string>
    <string name="GEOMATICS">SURVEYING AND GEOMATICS</string>
    <string name="CONSTRUCTIONS">MATERIALS TESTING AND CONSTRUCTION PRACTICES</string>
    <string name="SOLOD">INTRODUCTION TO SOLID MECHANICS</string>
    <string name="HYDRA">HYDRAULIC ENGINEERING AND MACHINES</string>


    CIVIL third year
    <string name="GE">GEOTECHNICAL ENGINEERING</string>
    <string name="STRUCTURE">DESIGN OF STRUCTURE-1</string>
    <string name="ESTIMATION">QUANTITY ESTIMATION AND MANAGEMENT</string>
    <string name="MC">MODERN CONSTRUCTION</string>
    <string name="INDUSTRIAL_CIV">INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT</string>
    <string name="CYBER_CIV">CYBER SECURITY</string>
    <string name="ECO">ENVIRONMENTAL ENGINEERING</string>
    <string name="ECONOMICS_CIV">MANAGERIAL ECONOMICS</string>
    <string name="TRANSPORT">TRANSPORTATION ENGINEERING</string>
    <string name="SOCIOLOGY_CIV">SOCIOLOGY</string>
    <string name="FD">FOUNDATION DESIGN</string>
    <string name="STRUCTURE_2">DESIGN OF STRUCTURE-2</string>
    <string name="play">play</string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS DATABASE
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_DATABASE">Introduction: Overview, Database System vs File System, Database System Concept and Architecture, Data Model Schema and Instances, Data Independence and Database Language and Interfaces, Data Definitions Language, DML, Overall Database Structure. Data Modeling Using the Entity Relationship Model: ER Model Concepts, Notation for ER Diagram, Mapping Constraints, Keys, Concepts of Super Key, Candidate Key, Primary Key, Generalization, Aggregation, Reduction of an ER Diagrams to Tables, Extended ER Model, Relationship of Higher Degree.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_DATABASE">Relational data Model and Language: Relational Data Model Concepts, Integrity  Constraints, Entity Integrity, Referential Integrity, Keys Constraints, Domain Constraints, Relational Algebra, Relational Calculus, Tuple and Domain Calculus. Introduction on SQL: Characteristics of SQL, Advantage of SQL. SQl Data Type and Literals. Types of SQL Commands. SQL Operators and Their Procedure. Tables, Views and Indexes. Queries and Sub Queries. Aggregate Functions. Insert, Update and Delete Operations, Joins, Unions, Intersection, Minus, Cursors, Triggers, Procedures in SQL/PL SQL
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_DATABASE">Data Base Design and Normalization: Functional dependencies, normal forms, first, second, 8 third normal forms, BCNF, inclusion dependence, loss less join decompositions, normalization using FD, MVD, and JDs, alternative approaches to database design </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_DATABASE">Transaction Processing Concept: Transaction System, Testing of Serializability, Serializability of Schedules, Conflict and View Serializable Schedule, Recoverability, Recovery from Transaction Failures, Log Based Recovery, Checkpoints, Deadlock Handling. Distributed Database: Distributed Data Storage, Concurrency Control, Directory System.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_DATABASE">Concurrency Control Techniques: Concurrency Control, Locking Techniques for  Concurrency Control, Time Stamping Protocols for Concurrency Control, Validation Based Protocol, Multiple Granularity, Multi Version Schemes, Recovery with Concurrent Transaction, Case Study of Oracle.
 </string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS DAA
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_DAA">Introduction: Algorithms, Analyzing Algorithms, Complexity of Algorithms, Growth  of Functions, Performance Measurements, Sorting and Order Statistics - Shell Sort, Quick Sort, Merge Sort, Heap Sort, Comparison of Sorting Algorithms, Sorting in Linear Time.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_DAA">Advanced Data Structures: Red-Black Trees, B – Trees, Binomial Heaps, Fibonacci Heaps, Tries, Skip List </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS_DAA">Divide and Conquer with Examples Such as Sorting, Matrix Multiplication, Convex Hull and Searching. Greedy Methods with Examples Such as Optimal Reliability Allocation, Knapsack, Minimum Spanning Trees – Prim’s and Kruskal’s Algorithms, Single Source Shortest Paths - Dijkstra’s and Bellman Ford Algorithms.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_DAA">Dynamic Programming with Examples Such as Knapsack. All Pair Shortest Paths – Warshal’s and Floyd’s Algorithms, Resource Allocation Problem. Backtracking, Branch and Bound with Examples Such as Travelling Salesman Problem, Graph Coloring, n-Queen Problem, Hamiltonian Cycles and Sum of Subsets. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_DAA">Selected Topics: Algebraic Computation, Fast Fourier Transform, String Matching, Theory of NP-Completeness, Approximation Algorithms and Randomized Algorithms </string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS PPL
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_PPL">Introduction: Role of Programming Languages: Why Programming Languages, Towards Higher-Level Languages, Programming Paradigms, Programming Environments Language Description: Syntactic Structure, Language Translation Issues: Programming Language Syntax, Stages in Translation, Formal Translation Models
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_PPL">Data, Data Types, and Basic Statements : Names , Variables , Binding, Type Checking, Scope, Scope Rules , Lifetime and Garbage  Collection, Primitive Data Types, Strings, Array Types, Associative Arrays ,Record Types, Union Types, Pointers and References , Arithmetic Expressions , Overloaded Operators, Type Conversions , Relational and Boolean Expressions, Assignment Statements, Mixed Mode Assignments, Control Structures, Selection ,Iterations, Branching, Guarded  Statements </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_PPL">Subprograms and Implementations : Subprograms, Design Issues, Local Referencing, Parameter Passing, Overloaded Methods, Generic Methods, Design Issues for Functions , Semantics of Call and Return, Implementing Simple Subprograms, Stack and Dynamic Local Variables, Nested Subprograms, Dynamic Scoping. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_PPL">Object-Orientation, Concurrency, and Event Handling : Grouping of Data and Operations — Constructs for Programming Structures, Abstraction Information Hiding, Program Design with Modules, Defined Types, Object Oriented Programming — Concept of Object, Inheritance, Derived Classes and Information Hiding – Templates, Semaphores, Monitors, Message Passing, Threads, Statement Level Concurrency  Exception Handling (Using C++ and Java as Example Language).
   </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_PPL"> Functional and Logic Programming Languages : Introduction to Lambda Calculus , Fundamentals of Functional Programming Languages, Programming with Programming with ML, Introduction to Logic and Logic Programming – Programming with Prolog. </string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS COMPILER
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_COMPILER">Introduction to Compiler: Phases and passes, Bootstrapping, Finite  state machines and regular expressions and their applications to lexical analysis, Optimization of DFA-Based Pattern Matchers implementation of lexical analyzers, lexical-analyzer generator, LEX compiler, Formal grammars and their application to syntax analysis, BNF notation, ambiguity, YACC. The syntactic specification of programming languages: Context free grammars, derivation and parse trees, capabilities of CFG. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_COMPILER">Basic Parsing Techniques: Parsers, Shift reduce parsing, operator precedence parsing, top down parsing, predictive parsers Automatic Construction of efficient Parsers: LR parsers, the canonical Collection of LR(0) items, constructing SLR parsing tables, constructing Canonical LR parsing tables, Constructing LALR parsing tables, using ambiguous grammars, an automatic parser generator, implementation of LR parsing tables</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_COMPILER">Syntax-directed Translation: Syntax-directed Translation schemes, Implementation of Syntax-directed Translators, Intermediate code, postfix notation, Parse trees and syntax trees, three address code, quadruple and triples, translation of assignment statements, Boolean expressions, statements that alter the flow of control, postfix translation, translation with a top down parser. More about translation: Array references in arithmetic expressions, procedures call, declarations and case statements. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_COMPILER">Symbol Tables: Data structure for symbols tables, representing scope information. RunTime Administration: Implementation of simple stack allocation scheme, storage allocation in block structured language. Error Detection and Recovery: Lexical Phase errors, syntactic phase errors semantic errors. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_COMPILER"> Code Generation: Design Issues, the Target Language. Addresses in the Target Code, Basic Blocks and Flow Graphs, Optimization of Basic Blocks, Code Generator. Code optimization: Machine-Independent Optimizations, Loop optimization, DAG representation of basic blocks, value numbers and algebraic laws, Global Data-Flow analysis. </string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS CYBER SECURITY
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_CYBER">Introduction- Introduction to Information Systems, Types of Information
Systems, Development of Information Systems, Introduction to Information
Security, Need for Information Security, Threats to Information Systems,
Information Assurance, Cyber Security, and Security Risk Analysis.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_CYBER">Application Security- (Database, E-mail and Internet), Data Security
Considerations-Backups, Archival Storage and Disposal of Data, Security
Technology-Firewall and VPNs, Intrusion Detection, Access Control. Security
Threats -Viruses, Worms, Trojan Horse, Bombs, Trapdoors, Spoofs, E-mail
Viruses, Macro Viruses, Malicious Software, Network and Denial of Services
Attack, Security Threats to E-Commerce- Electronic Payment System, e- Cash,
Credit/Debit Cards. Digital Signature, Public Key Cryptography
</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_CYBER">Developing Secure Information Systems- Application Development
Security, Information Security Governance and Risk Management, Security
Architecture and Design Security Issues in Hardware, Data Storage and
Downloadable Devices, Physical Security of IT Assets, Access Control, CCTV
and Intrusion Detection Systems, Backup Security Measures.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_CYBER">
Security Policies- Development of Policies, WWW Policies, Email Security
Policies, Policy Review Process-Corporate Policies-Sample Security Policies,
Publishing and Notification Requirement of the Policies.
Evolving Technology Security – Mobile, Cloud, Outsourcing, SCM.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_CYBER">Information Security Standards-ISO, IT Act, Copyright Act, Patent Law,
IPR. Cyber Laws in India; IT Act 2000 Provisions, Intellectual Property Law:
Copy Right Law, Software License, Semiconductor Law and Patent Law.
Case Study – Corporate Security
</string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS DATAMINING
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_DATAMINING">Data Warehousing: Overview, Definition, Data Warehousing Components,  Building a Data Warehouse, Warehouse Database, Mapping the Data Warehouse to a Multiprocessor Architecture, Difference between Database System and Data Warehouse, Multi Dimensional Data Model, Data Cubes, Stars, Snow Flakes, Fact Constellations, Concept
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_DATAMINING">Data Warehouse Process and Technology: Warehousing Strategy, Warehouse  /management and Support Processes, Warehouse Planning and Implementation, Hardware and Operating Systems for Data Warehousing, Client/Server Computing Model and Data Warehousing. Parallel Processors and Cluster Systems, Distributed DBMS implementations, Warehousing Software, Warehouse Schema Design,
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_DATAMINING">Data Mining: Overview, Motivation, Definition and Functionalities, Data Processing, Form of Data Pre-processing, Data Cleaning: Missing Values, Noisy Data, (Binning, Clustering, Regression, Computer and Human inspection), Inconsistent Data, Data Integration and Transformation. Data Reduction:-Data Cube Aggregation, Dimensionality reduction, Data Compression, Numerosity Reduction, Discretization and Concept hierarchy generation, Decision Tree.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_DATAMINING">Classification: Definition, Data Generalization, Analytical Characterization,  Analysis of attribute relevance, Mining Class comparisons, Statistical measures in large Databases, Statistical-Based Algorithms, Distance-Based Algorithms, Decision Tree-Based Algorithms. Clustering: Introduction, Similarity and Distance Measures, Hierarchical and Partitional Algorithms. Hierarchical Clustering- CURE and Chameleon. Density Based MethodsDBSCAN, OPTICS. Grid Based Methods- STING, CLIQUE. Model Based Method – Statistical Approach, Association rules: Introduction, Large Item sets, Basic Algorithms, Parallel and Distributed Algorithms, Neural Network approach. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_DATAMINING">Data Visualization and Overall Perspective: Aggregation, Historical information, Query Facility, OLAP function and Tools. OLAP Servers, ROLAP, MOLAP, HOLAP, Data Mining interface, Security, Backup and Recovery, Tuning Data Warehouse, Testing Data Warehouse. Warehousing applications and Recent Trends: Types of Warehousing Applications, Web Mining, Spatial Mining and Temporal Mining
</string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS WEBTECH
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_WEBTECH">Introduction:  Introduction and Web Development Strategies, History of Web and Internet, Protocols Governing Web, Writing Web Projects, Connecting to Internet, Introduction to Internet services and tools, Introduction to client-server computing. Core Java: Introduction, Operator, Data type, Variable, Arrays, Methods and Classes, Inheritance, Package and Interface, Exception Handling, Multithread programming, I/O, Java Applet, String handling, Event handling, Introduction to AWT, AWT controls, Layout managers
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_WEBTECH">Web Page Designing: HTML: List, Table, Images, Frames, forms, CSS, Document type definition, XML: DTD, XML schemes, Object Models, presenting and using XML, Using XML Processors: DOM and SAX, Dynamic HTML </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_WEBTECH">Scripting:  Java script: Introduction, documents, forms, statements, functions, objects; introduction to AJAX, Networking : Internet  Addressing,  InetAddress,  Factory  Methods,  Instance  Methods,  TCP/IP  Client Sockets, URL, URL Connection, TCP/IP Server Sockets, Datagram. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_WEBTECH">Enterprise Java Bean: Preparing a Class to be a JavaBeans, Creating a JavaBeans, JavaBeans Properties, Types of beans, Stateful Session bean, Stateless Session bean, Entity bean Java  Database  Connectivity  (JDBC): Merging  Data  from  Multiple  Tables:  Joining,  Manipul ating, Databases with JDBC, Prepared Statements, Transaction Processing, Stored Procedures. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_WEBTECH">Servlets:  Servlet  Overview  and  Architecture,  Interface  Servlet  and  the  Servlet  Life  Cycle,  H andling HTTP  get  Requests,  Handling  HTTP  post  Requests,  Redirecting  Requests  to  Other  Resource s,  Session Tracking, Cookies, Session Tracking with Http Session Java Server  Pages  (JSP): Introduction,  Java Server  Pages  Overview, A  First  Java Server  Page  Example, Implicit Objects, Scripting, Standard Actions, Directives, Custom Tag Libraries.. </string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS SOCIOLOGY
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_SOCIOLOGY">Industrial Sociology: Nature, Scope and Importance of Industrial Sociology.
Social Relations in Industry, Social Organisation in Industry- Bureaucracy,
Scientific Management and Human Relations.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_SOCIOLOGY">Rise and Development of Industry: Early Industrialism – Types of Productive
Systems – The Manorial or Feudal system. The Guild system, The domestic or
putting-out system, and the Factory system. Characteristics of the factory system.
Causes and Consequences of industrialization. Obstacles to and Limitations of
Industrialization.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_SOCIOLOGY">Industrialization in India. Industrial Policy Resolutions – 1956.Science.
Technology and Innovation Policy of India 2013.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_SOCIOLOGY">Contemporary Issues: Grievances and Grievance handling Procedure. Industrial
Disputes: causes, Strikes and Lockouts. Preventive Machinery of Industrial
Disputes: Schemes of Workers Participation in Management- Works Committee,
Collective Bargaining, Bi-partite and Tri-partite Agreement, Code of Discipline,
Standing Orders. Labour courts and Industrial Tribunals.</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_SOCIOLOGY">Visualizing the future: Models of industrialization- Collectivist, anarchist, free
market, environmentalist, etc. Cultural issues, consumer society and sociological
concerns.</string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS ECONOMICS
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_ECONOMICS">Introduction of Engineering Economics and Demand Analysis: Meaning
and nature of Economics, Relation between science, engineering, technology
and economics; Meaning of Demand, Determinants of Demand, Shifts in
demand, Law of Demand, Price Elasticity of Demand and Types, Income
Elasticity, Cross price Elasticity, Determinants of Elasticity, uses and
importance of elasticity.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_ECONOMICS">Concept of Supply: Law of Supply, Factors affecting Supply, Elasticity of
supply.
Demand Forecasting: Introduction, Meaning and Forecasting, Methods or
Techniques of Demand Forecasting, Criteria for Good Demand Forecasting,
Demand Forecasting for a New Product;</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_ECONOMICS">Cost Analysis- Introduction, Types of Costs, Cost-Output Relationship: Cost
Function, Cost-Output Relationships in the Short Run, and Cost-Output
Relationships in the Long Run; Short run and long run, Break- Even Analysis;
Production functions: laws of variable proportions, law of returns; Economies
of scale: Internal and external.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_ECONOMICS">Market Structure: Market Structure Perfect Competition, Imperfect
competition – Monopolistic, Oligopoly, duopoly sorbent features of price
determination and various market conditions.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_ECONOMICS">Nature and characteristics of Indian economy, concepts of LPG, elementary
concepts of National Income, Inflation and Business Cycles ,Concept of N.I.
and Measurement., Meaning of Inflation, Types and causes , Phases of
business cycle .Investment decisions for boosting economy(National income
and per capital income)</string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS GRAPHICS
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_GRAPHICS">Introduction and Line Generation: Types of computer graphics, Graphic Displays- Random scan displays, Raster scan displays, Frame buffer and video controller, Points and lines, Line drawing algorithms, Circle generating algorithms, Mid-point circle generating algorithm, and parallel version of these algorithms. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_GRAPHICS">Transformations: Basic transformation, Matrix representations and homogenous coordinates, Composite transformations, Reflections and shearing.  Windowing and Clipping: Viewing pipeline, Viewing transformations, 2-D Clipping algorithms- Line clipping algorithms such as Cohen Sutherland line clipping algorithm, Liang Barsky algorithm, Line clipping against non rectangular clip windows; Polygon clipping – Sutherland Hodgeman polygon clipping, Weiler and Atherton polygon clipping, Curve clipping, Text clipping
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_GRAPHICS">Three Dimensional: 3-D Geometric Primitives, 3-D Object representation, 3-D Transformation, 3-D viewing, projections, 3-D Clipping.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_GRAPHICS">Curves and Surfaces:  Quadric surfaces, Spheres, Ellipsoid, Blobby objects, Introductory concepts of Spline, Bspline and Bezier curves and surfaces.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_GRAPHICS"> Hidden Lines and Surfaces: Back Face Detection algorithm, Depth buffer method, A- buffer method, Scan line method, basic illumination models– Ambient light, Diffuse reflection, Specular reflection and Phong model, Combined approach, Warn model, Intensity Attenuation, Color consideration, Transparency and Shadows. </string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS MANAGEMENT
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_MANEGEMENT">Introduction: Concept and scope of Industrial Management. Productivity:
Definition, measurement, productivity index, types of production system,
Industrial Ownership.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_MANEGEMENT">Functions of Management, Taylor’s Scientific Management Theory, Fayol’s
Principles of Management, Social responsibilities of Management,
Introduction to Human resources management: Nature of HRM, functions and
importance of HRM.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_MANEGEMENT">Work Study: Introduction, definition, objectives, steps in work study, Method
study: definition, objectives, steps of method study, Work Measurement: purpose,
types of study — stop watch methods — steps — allowances — standard time
calculations — work sampling, Production Planning and Control
Inventory Control: Inventory, Cost, Models of inventory control: EOQ, ABC,
VED</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_MANEGEMENT">Quality Control: statistical quality control, Control charts for variables and
attributes, Acceptance Sampling- Single sampling- Double sampling plans,
Introduction to TQM. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_MANEGEMENT">Project Management: Project network analysis, CPM, PERT and Project
crashing and resource Leveling

</string>


    CS3YEAR SYLLABUS NETWORKS
    <string name="UNIT1_CS3_NETWORKS">Introduction Concepts: Goals and Applications of Networks, Network structure and  architecture, The OSI reference model, services, Network Topology Design - Delay Analysis, Back Bone Design, Local Access Network Design, Physical Layer Transmission Media, Switching methods, ISDN, Terminal Handling
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS3_NETWORKS">Medium Access sub layer: Medium Access sub layer - Channel Allocations, LAN protocols - ALOHA protocols - Overview of IEEE standards - FDDI. Data Link Layer - Elementary Data Link Protocols, Sliding Window protocols, Error Handling.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS3_NETWORKS">Network Layer: Network Layer - Point - to Pont Networks, routing, Congestion control Internetworking -TCP / IP, IP packet, IP address, IPv6. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS3_NETWORKS">Transport Layer: Transport Layer - Design issues, connection management, session  Layer-Design issues, remote procedure call. Presentation Layer-Design issues, Data compression techniques, cryptography - TCP - Window Management. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS3_NETWORKS"> Application Layer: Application Layer: File Transfer, Access and Management, Electronic mail, Virtual Terminals, Other application. Example Networks - Internet and Public Networks </string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS MACHINE DESIGN 1
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN1"> Definition, Design requirements of machine elements, Design procedure, Standards in design, Selection of preferred sizes, Indian Standards designation of carbon and alloy steels, Selection of materials for static and fatigue loads.
 Design for Static Load
 Modes of failure, Factor of safety, Principal stresses, Stresses due to bending and torsion, Theory of failure.

  </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN1">
 Design for Fluctuating Loads Cyclic stresses, Fatigue and endurance limit, Stress concentration factor,Stress concentration factor for various machine parts, Notch sensitivity, Design for finite and infinite life, Soderberg, Goodman and Gerber criteria.
   Riveted Joints
 Riveting methods, materials, Types of rivet heads, Types of riveted joints, Caulking and Fullering, Failure of riveted joint, Efficiency of riveted joint, Design of boiler joints, Eccentric loaded riveted joint.  </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN1">Shafts
 Cause of failure in shafts, Materials for shaft, Stresses in shafts, Design of shafts subjected to twisting moment, bending moment and combined twisting and bending moments, Shafts subjected to fatigue loads, Design for rigidity. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN1">Mechanical Springs
 Types, Material for helical springs, End connections for compression and tension helical springs, Stresses and deflection of helical springs of circular wire, Design of helical springs subjected to static and fatigue loading.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN1">Keys and Couplings
 Types of keys, splines, Selection of square and flat keys, Strength of sunk key, Couplings, Design of rigid and flexible couplings.
 Power Screws
 Forms of threads, multiple threads, Efficiency of square threads, Trapezoidal threads, Stresses in screws, Design of screw jack </string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS CYBER SECURITY
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_CYBER">Introduction- Introduction to Information Systems, Types of Information
Systems, Development of Information Systems, Introduction to Information
Security, Need for Information Security, Threats to Information Systems,
Information Assurance, Cyber Security, and Security Risk Analysis.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_CYBER">Application Security- (Database, E-mail and Internet), Data Security
Considerations-Backups, Archival Storage and Disposal of Data, Security
Technology-Firewall and VPNs, Intrusion Detection, Access Control. Security
Threats -Viruses, Worms, Trojan Horse, Bombs, Trapdoors, Spoofs, E-mail
Viruses, Macro Viruses, Malicious Software, Network and Denial of Services
Attack, Security Threats to E-Commerce- Electronic Payment System, e- Cash,
Credit/Debit Cards. Digital Signature, Public Key Cryptography
</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_CYBER">Developing Secure Information Systems- Application Development
Security, Information Security Governance and Risk Management, Security
Architecture and Design Security Issues in Hardware, Data Storage and
Downloadable Devices, Physical Security of IT Assets, Access Control, CCTV
and Intrusion Detection Systems, Backup Security Measures.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_CYBER">
Security Policies- Development of Policies, WWW Policies, Email Security
Policies, Policy Review Process-Corporate Policies-Sample Security Policies,
Publishing and Notification Requirement of the Policies.
Evolving Technology Security – Mobile, Cloud, Outsourcing, SCM.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_CYBER">Information Security Standards-ISO, IT Act, Copyright Act, Patent Law,
IPR. Cyber Laws in India; IT Act 2000 Provisions, Intellectual Property Law:
Copy Right Law, Software License, Semiconductor Law and Patent Law.
Case Study – Corporate Security
</string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS ECONOMICS
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_ECONOMICS">Introduction of Engineering Economics and Demand Analysis: Meaning
and nature of Economics, Relation between science, engineering, technology
and economics; Meaning of Demand, Determinants of Demand, Shifts in
demand, Law of Demand, Price Elasticity of Demand and Types, Income
Elasticity, Cross price Elasticity, Determinants of Elasticity, uses and
importance of elasticity.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_ECONOMICS">Concept of Supply: Law of Supply, Factors affecting Supply, Elasticity of
supply.
Demand Forecasting: Introduction, Meaning and Forecasting, Methods or
Techniques of Demand Forecasting, Criteria for Good Demand Forecasting,
Demand Forecasting for a New Product;</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_ECONOMICS">Cost Analysis- Introduction, Types of Costs, Cost-Output Relationship: Cost
Function, Cost-Output Relationships in the Short Run, and Cost-Output
Relationships in the Long Run; Short run and long run, Break- Even Analysis;
Production functions: laws of variable proportions, law of returns; Economies
of scale: Internal and external.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_ECONOMICS">Market Structure: Market Structure Perfect Competition, Imperfect
competition – Monopolistic, Oligopoly, duopoly sorbent features of price
determination and various market conditions.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_ECONOMICS">Nature and characteristics of Indian economy, concepts of LPG, elementary
concepts of National Income, Inflation and Business Cycles ,Concept of N.I.
and Measurement., Meaning of Inflation, Types and causes , Phases of
business cycle .Investment decisions for boosting economy(National income
and per capital income)</string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS MANAGEMENT
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_MANAGEMENT">Introduction: Concept and scope of Industrial Management. Productivity:
Definition, measurement, productivity index, types of production system,
Industrial Ownership.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_MANAGEMENT">Functions of Management, Taylor’s Scientific Management Theory, Fayol’s
Principles of Management, Social responsibilities of Management,
Introduction to Human resources management: Nature of HRM, functions and
importance of HRM.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_MANAGEMENT">Work Study: Introduction, definition, objectives, steps in work study, Method
study: definition, objectives, steps of method study, Work Measurement: purpose,
types of study — stop watch methods — steps — allowances — standard time
calculations — work sampling, Production Planning and Control
Inventory Control: Inventory, Cost, Models of inventory control: EOQ, ABC,
VED</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_MANAGEMENT">Quality Control: statistical quality control, Control charts for variables and
attributes, Acceptance Sampling- Single sampling- Double sampling plans,
Introduction to TQM. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_MANAGEMENT">Project Management: Project network analysis, CPM, PERT and Project
crashing and resource Leveling

</string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS SOCIOLOGY
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_SOCIOLOGY">Industrial Sociology: Nature, Scope and Importance of Industrial Sociology.
Social Relations in Industry, Social Organisation in Industry- Bureaucracy,
Scientific Management and Human Relations.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_SOCIOLOGY">Rise and Development of Industry: Early Industrialism – Types of Productive
Systems – The Manorial or Feudal system. The Guild system, The domestic or
putting-out system, and the Factory system. Characteristics of the factory system.
Causes and Consequences of industrialization. Obstacles to and Limitations of
Industrialization.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_SOCIOLOGY">Industrialization in India. Industrial Policy Resolutions – 1956.Science.
Technology and Innovation Policy of India 2013.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_SOCIOLOGY">Contemporary Issues: Grievances and Grievance handling Procedure. Industrial
Disputes: causes, Strikes and Lockouts. Preventive Machinery of Industrial
Disputes: Schemes of Workers Participation in Management- Works Committee,
Collective Bargaining, Bi-partite and Tri-partite Agreement, Code of Discipline,
Standing Orders. Labour courts and Industrial Tribunals.</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_SOCIOLOGY">Visualizing the future: Models of industrialization- Collectivist, anarchist, free
market, environmentalist, etc. Cultural issues, consumer society and sociological
concerns.</string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS FLUID MACHINERY
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_FLUID_MACHINERY">Introduction: Impulse of Jet and Impulse Turbines:
 Classification of Fluid Machines and Devices, Application of momentum and moment of momentum equation to flow through hydraulic machinery, Euler’s fundamental equation. Introduction to hydrodynamic thrust of jet on a fixed and moving surface (flat and curve), Classification of turbines, Impulse turbines, Constructional details, Velocitytriangles, Power and efficiency calculations, Governing of Pelton wheel </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_FLUID_MACHINERY">Reaction Turbines:
 Francis and Kaplan turbines, Constructional details, Velocity triangles, Power and efficiency calculations, Degree of reaction, Draft tube, Cavitation in turbines, Principles of similarity, Unit and specific speed, Performance characteristics, Selection of water turbines. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_FLUID_MACHINERY">Pumps:
 Classifications of centrifugal pumps, Vector diagram, Work done by impellor, Efficiencies of centrifugal pumps, Specific speed, Cavitation and separation, Performance characteristics</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_FLUID_MACHINERY">Positive Displacement and other Pumps:
 Reciprocating pump theory, Slip, Indicator diagram, Effect of acceleration, air vessels, Comparison of centrifugal and reciprocating pumps, Performance characteristics. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_FLUID_MACHINERY">Hydraulic accumulator, Hydraulic intensifier, Hydraulic Press, hydraulic crane, hydraulic lift, hydraulic Ram,hydraulic coupling, hydraulic torque converter, air lift pump, jet pump.</string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS HEAT AND MASS
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_HEAT_AND_MASS">Introduction to Heat Transfer:
 Thermodynamics and Heat Transfer. Modes of Heat Transfer: Conduction, convection and radiation. Effect of temperature on thermal conductivity of materials; Introduction to combined heat transfer mechanism.
  Conduction :
 General differential heat conduction equation in the rectangular, cylindrical and spherical coordinate systems.Initial and boundary conditions.
   Steady State one-dimensional Heat conduction :
 Simple and Composite Systems in rectangular, cylindrical and spherical coordinates with and without energy generation; Concept of thermal resistance.Analogy between heat and electricity flow; Thermal contact resistance and over all heat transfer coefficient; Critical radius of insulation.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_HEAT_AND_MASS">Heat transfer from extended surfaces, Fins of uniform cross-sectional area; Errors of measurement of temperature in thermometer wells.
   Transient Conduction:
 Transient heat conduction; Lumped capacitance method; Time constant; Unsteady state heat conduction in one dimension only, Heisler charts.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_HEAT_AND_MASS">Forced Convection:
 Basic concepts; Hydrodynamic boundary layer; Thermal boundary layer; Approximate integral boundary layer analysis; Analogy between momentum and heat transfer in turbulent flow over a flat surface; Mixed boundary layer; Flow over a flat plate; Flow across a single cylinder and a sphere; Flow inside ducts; Thermal entrance region, Empirical heat transfer relations; Relation between fluid friction and heat transfer; Liquid metal heat transfer.
        Natural Convection :
 Physical mechanism of natural convection; Buoyant force; Empirical heat transfer relations for natural convection over vertical planes and cylinders, horizontal plates and cylinders, and sphere, Combined free and forced convection.  </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_HEAT_AND_MASS">Thermal Radiation :
 Basic radiation concepts; Radiation properties of surfaces; Black body radiation Planck’s law, Wein’s displacement law, Stefan Boltzmann law, Kirchoff law; ; Gray body; Shape factor; Black-body radiation; Radiation exchange between diffuse non black bodies in an enclosure; Radiation shields; Radiation combined with conduction and convection; Absorption and emission in gaseous medium; Solar radiation; Green house effect.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_HEAT_AND_MASS">Heat Exchanger :
 Types of heat exchangers; Fouling factors; Overall heat transfer coefficient; Logarithmic mean temperature difference (LMTD) method; Effectiveness-NTU method; Compact heat exchangers.
   Condensation and Boiling:
 Introduction to condensation phenomena; Heat transfer relations for laminar film condensation on vertical surfaces and on outside and inside of a horizontal tube; Effect of non-condensable gases; Dropwise condensation; Heat pipes; Boiling modes, pool boiling; Hysteresis in boiling curve; Forced convection boiling.  Introduction to Mass Transfer:
 Introduction; Fick law of diffusion; Steady state equimolar counter diffusion; Steady state diffusion though a stagnant gas film. </string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS IC ENGINES
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_IC_ENGINES">Introduction to I.C Engines: Engine classification and basic terminology, Two and four stroke engines, SI and CI engines, Valve timing diagram.
 Thermodynamic analysis of Air standard cycles, Otto cycle, Diesel cycle, Dual cycle, Stirling cycle, Ericsson cycles, Comparison of Otto, Diesel and Dual cycles
 Fuel air cycle, factors affecting the fuel air cycle, Actual cycle. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_IC_ENGINES">SI Engines: Combustion in SI engine, Flame speed, Ignition delay, Abnormal combustion and it control, combustion chamber design for SI engines.
 Carburetion, Mixture requirements, Carburetors and fuel injection system in SI Engine
 Ignition system requirements, Magneto and battery ignition systems, ignition timing and spark plug, Electronic ignition, Scavenging in 2 Stroke engines, Supercharging and its effect </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_IC_ENGINES">CI Engine: Combustion in CI engines, Ignition delay, Knock and it control, Combustion chamber design of CI engines.
 Fuel injection in CI engines, Requirements, Types of injection systems, Fuel pumps, Fuel injectors, Injection timings
 Exhaust emissions from SI engine and CI engine  and it control </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_IC_ENGINES">Engine Cooling and Lubrication: Different cooling systems, Radiators and cooling fans, Engine friction, Lubrication principle, Type of lubrication, Lubrication oils, Crankcase ventilation.
 Fuels: Fuels for SI and CI engine , Important qualities of SI and CI engine fuels, Rating of SI engine and CI engine fuels, Dopes, Additives, Gaseous fuels, LPG, CNG, Biogas, Producer gas, Alternative fuels for IC engines.
 Testing and Performance: Performance parameters, Basic measurements, Blow by measurement, Testing of SI and CI engines </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_IC_ENGINES">Compressors: Classification, Reciprocating compressors, Single and Multi stage compressors, Intercooling, Volumetric efficiency.
 Rotary compressors, Classification, Centrifugal compressor , Axial compressors, Surging and stalling, Roots blower, Vaned compressor. </string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS MACHINE DESIGN 2
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN2">
 Tooth forms, System of gear teeth, contact ratio, Standard proportions of gear systems, Interference in involute gears, Backlash, Selection of gear materials, Gear manufacturing methods, Design considerations, Beam strength of gear tooth, Dynamic tooth load, Wear strength of gear tooth, Failure of gear tooth, Design of spur gears, AGMA and Indian standards.
    Helical Gears
 Terminology, Proportions for helical gears, Forces components on a tooth of helical gear, Virtual number of teeth, Beam strength and wear strength of helical gears, Dynamic load on helical gears, Design of helical gears. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN2">gears
 Terminology of bevel gears, Force analysis, Virtual number of teeth, Beam strength and wear strength of bevel gears,Effective load of gear tooth, Design of a bevel gear system.
   Worm Gears
 Types of worms, Terminology, Gear tooth proportions, Efficiency of worm gears, Heat dissipation in worm gearing, Strength and wear tooth load for worm gears, Design of worm gearing system.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN2">Sliding Contact Bearing
 Types, Selection of bearing, Plain journal bearing, Hydrodynamic lubrication, Properties and materials, Lubricants and lubrication, Hydrodynamic journal bearing, Heat generation, Design of journal bearing, Thrust bearing-pivot and collar bearing, Hydrodynamic thrust bearing, </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN2">Rolling Contact Bearing
 Advantages and disadvantages, Types of ball bearing, Thrust ball bearing, Types of roller bearing, Selection of radial ball bearing, Bearing life, Selection of roller bearings, Dynamic equivalent load for roller contact bearing under constant and variable loading, Reliability of Bearing, Selection of rolling contact bearing, Lubrication of ball and roller bearing, Mounting of bearing </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_MACHINE_DESIGN2">IC ENGINE parts,
 Selection of type of IC engine, General design considerations, Design of cylinder and cylinder head; Design of piston and its parts like piston ring and gudgeon pin etc.; Design of connecting rod; Design of crankshaft
 </string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS MANUFACTURING SCIENCE
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_MANUFACTURING_SCIENCE">Metal Cutting-
 Mechanics of metal cutting. Geometry of tool and nomenclature .ASA system Orthogonal vs. oblique cutting. Mechanics of chip formation, types of chips. Shear angle relationship. Merchant’s force circle diagram. Cutting forces, power required. Heat generation and cutting tool temperature, Cutting fluids/lubricants. Tool materials. Tool wear and tool life. Machinability. Dynamometer, Brief introduction to machine tool vibration and surface finish. Economics of metal cutting</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_MANUFACTURING_SCIENCE">Machine Tools
 (i) Lathe: Principle, construction, types, operations, Turret/capstan, semi/Automatic, Tool layout
   (ii) Shaper, slotter, planer: Construction, operations and drives.
   (iii) Milling: Construction, Milling cutters, up and down milling. Dividing head and indexing. Max chip thickness and power required.
   (iv) Drilling and boring: Drilling, boring, reaming tools. Geometry of twist drills. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_MANUFACTURING_SCIENCE">Grinding and Super finishing
 (i) Grinding: Grinding wheels, abrasive and bonds, cutting action. Grinding wheel specification. Grinding wheel wear - attritions wear, fracture wear. Dressing and Truing. Max chip thickness and Guest criteria. Surface and cylindrical grinding.Centerless grinding
   (ii) Super finishing: Honing, lapping and polishing.
   Limits, Fits and Tolerance and Surface roughness:
 Introduction to Limits, Fits, Tolerances and IS standards, Limit-gauges, and surface-roughness.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_MANUFACTURING_SCIENCE">B. Metal Joining (Welding)
 Survey of welding and allied processes. Gas welding and cutting, process and equipment. Arc welding: Power sources and consumables. TIG and MIG processes and their parameters. Resistance welding - spot, seam projection etc. Other welding processes such as atomic hydrogen, submerged arc, electroslag, friction welding. Soldering and Brazing. Adhesive bonding. Thermodynamic and Metallurgical aspects in welding and weld, Weldability, Shrinkage/residual stress in welds. Distortions and Defects in welds andremedies. Weld decay in HAZ  </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_MANUFACTURING_SCIENCE">C. Introduction to Unconventional Machining and Welding
 Need and benefits, application and working principle of EDM, ECM, LBM, EBM, USM. AJM, WJM. Similarly, non-conventional welding applications such as LBW, USW, EBW, Plasma- arc welding, Diffusion welding, Explosive welding/cladding. Introduction to Hybrid machining processes
 </string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS RELIEBILITY
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_RELIEBILITY">Introduction: Definition of reliability, Failures and failures modes, Failure rates, MTTF, MTBF, Bath tub curve, Definition and factors influencing system effectiveness, various parameters of system effectiveness. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_RELIEBILITY">Reliability Mathematics, Definition of probability, laws of probability, conditional probability, Bay\'s theorem, Various probability distributions, Data collection, Recovery of data, Data analysis Procedures, Empirical reliability calculations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_RELIEBILITY">Reliability types, System of series, parallel, series parallel, Stand by and complex systems; Development of logic diagram, Methods of reliability evaluation; Cut set and tie set methods, Matrix methods, Event trees and fault trees methods, Reliability evaluation using probability distributions, The Weibull distribution and its application in reliability, Markov method, Frequency and duration method.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_RELIEBILITY">Reliability Improvements: Methods of reliability improvement, component redundancy, system redundancy, types of redundancies-series, parallel, series - parallel, stand by and hybrid, effect of maintenance
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_RELIEBILITY">Reliability Testing, Life testing, requirements, methods, test planning, data reporting system, data reduction and analysis, reliability test standards. </string>


    ME3YEAR SYLLABUS THEORY OF MACHINE
    <string name="UNIT1_ME3_THEORY_OF_MACHINE">Introduction, mechanisms and machines, kinematics and kinetics, types of links, kinematic pairs and their classification, types of constraint, degrees of freedom of planar mechanism, Grubler’s equation, mechanisms, inversion of four bar chain, slider crank chain and double slider crank chain.
 Velocity analysis:
 Introduction, velocity of point in mechanism, relative velocity method, velocities in four bar mechanism, instantaneous center .
 Acceleration analysis:
 Introduction, acceleration of a point on a link, acceleration diagram, Corioli’s component of acceleration, crank and slotted lever mechanism,. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME3_THEORY_OF_MACHINE">Cams
 Introduction, classification of cams and followers, cam profiles for knife edge, roller and flat faced followers for uniform velocity, uniform acceleration,

 Gears and gear trains
 Introduction, classification of gears, law of gearing, tooth forms and their comparisons, systems of gear teeth, length of path of contact, contact ratio, minimum number of teeth on gear and pinion to avoid interference, simple, compound, reverted and planetary gear trains, sun and planet gear train.   </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME3_THEORY_OF_MACHINE">Force analysis:
 Static force analysis of mechanisms, D’Alembert’s Principle, dynamics of rigid link in plane motion, dynamic force analysis of planar mechanisms, piston force and crank effort. Turning
 moment on crankshaft due to force on piston, Turning moment diagrams for single cylinder double acting steam engine, four stroke IC engine and multi-cylinder engines, Fluctuation of speed, Flywheel. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME3_THEORY_OF_MACHINE">Balancing :
 Introduction,static balance, dynamic balance, balancing of rotating masses,two plane balancing, graphical and analytical methods, balancing of reciprocating masses,
 Governors:
 Introduction, types of governors, characteristics of centrifugal governors, gravitycontrolled and spring controlled centrifugal governors, hunting of centrifugal governors, inertia </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME3_THEORY_OF_MACHINE">Brakes and dynamometers:
 Introduction, Law of friction and types of lubrication, types of brakes, effect of braking on rear and front wheels of a four wheeler, dynamometers, belt transmission dynamometer, torsion dynamometer, hydraulic dynamometer </string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS GEOTECHNICAL
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_GEOTECHNICAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_GEOTECHNICAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_GEOTECHNICAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_GEOTECHNICAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_GEOTECHNICAL"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS DESIGN OF STRUCTURE
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_DESIGN_OF_STRUCTURE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_DESIGN_OF_STRUCTURE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_DESIGN_OF_STRUCTURE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_DESIGN_OF_STRUCTURE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_DESIGN_OF_STRUCTURE"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS CYBER
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_CYBER"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS ENVIRONMENTAL
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_ENVIRONMENTAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_ENVIRONMENTAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_ENVIRONMENTAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_ENVIRONMENTAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_ENVIRONMENTAL"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS SOCIOLOGY
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS ECONOMICS
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_ECONOMICS"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS MANAGEMENT
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_MANAGEMENT"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS FOUNDATION_DESIGN
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_FOUNDATION_DESIGN"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_FOUNDATION_DESIGN"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_FOUNDATION_DESIGN"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_FOUNDATION_DESIGN"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_FOUNDATION_DESIGN"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS QUANTITY_ESTIMATION
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_QUANTITY_ESTIMATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_QUANTITY_ESTIMATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_QUANTITY_ESTIMATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_QUANTITY_ESTIMATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_QUANTITY_ESTIMATION"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS MODERN_CONSTRUCTION
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_MODERN_CONSTRUCTION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_MODERN_CONSTRUCTION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_MODERN_CONSTRUCTION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_MODERN_CONSTRUCTION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_MODERN_CONSTRUCTION"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS DESIGN_STRUCTURE_2
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_DESIGN_STRUCTURE_2"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_DESIGN_STRUCTURE_2"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_DESIGN_STRUCTURE_2"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_DESIGN_STRUCTURE_2"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_DESIGN_STRUCTURE_2"></string>


    CIVIL3YEAR SYLLABUS TRANSPORTATION
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL3_TRANSPORTATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL3_TRANSPORTATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL3_TRANSPORTATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL3_TRANSPORTATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL3_TRANSPORTATION"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS POWER_ELECTRONICS
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_POWER_ELECTRONICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_POWER_ELECTRONICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_POWER_ELECTRONICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_POWER_ELECTRONICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_POWER_ELECTRONICS"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS HIGH_VOLTAGE
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_HIGH_VOLTAGE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_HIGH_VOLTAGE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_HIGH_VOLTAGE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_HIGH_VOLTAGE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_HIGH_VOLTAGE"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS CYBER
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_CYBER"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS CONTROL_SYSTEM
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_CONTROL_SYSTEML"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_CONTROL_SYSTEML"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_CONTROL_SYSTEML"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_CONTROL_SYSTEML"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_CONTROL_SYSTEML"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS SOCIOLOGY
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS ECONOMICS
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_ECONOMICS"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS MANAGEMENT
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS2
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS2"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS2"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS2"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS2"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS2"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS MICROPROCESSOR
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_MICROPROCESSOR"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_MICROPROCESSOR"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_MICROPROCESSOR"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_MICROPROCESSOR"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_MICROPROCESSOR"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS POWER_SYSTEM_ANALYSIS
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_ANALYSIS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_ANALYSIS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_ANALYSIS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_ANALYSIS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_ANALYSIS"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS POWER_SYSTEM_OPTIMIZATION
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_OPTIMIZATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_OPTIMIZATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_OPTIMIZATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_OPTIMIZATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_POWER_SYSTEM_OPTIMIZATION"></string>


    EE3YEAR SYLLABUS POWER_TRANSMISSION
    <string name="UNIT1_EE3_POWER_TRANSMISSION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE3_POWER_TRANSMISSION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE3_POWER_TRANSMISSION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE3_POWER_TRANSMISSION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE3_POWER_TRANSMISSION"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS MICROWAVE_ENGINEERING
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_MICROWAVE_ENGINEERING"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_MICROWAVE_ENGINEERING"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_MICROWAVE_ENGINEERING"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_MICROWAVE_ENGINEERING"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_MICROWAVE_ENGINEERING"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS ANALOG_SIGNAL
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_ANALOG_SIGNAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_ANALOG_SIGNAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_ANALOG_SIGNAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_ANALOG_SIGNAL"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_ANALOG_SIGNAL"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS CYBER
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_CYBER"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_CYBER"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS ANTENNA_WAVE
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_ANTENNA_WAVE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_ANTENNA_WAVE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_ANTENNA_WAVE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_ANTENNA_WAVE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_ANTENNA_WAVE"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS SOCIOLOGY
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_SOCIOLOGY"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS ECONOMICS
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_ECONOMICS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_ECONOMICS"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS MANAGEMENT
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_MANAGEMENT"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS DIGITAL_COMMUNICATION
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_DIGITAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_DIGITAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_DIGITAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_DIGITAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_DIGITAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS DIGITAL_SIGNAL_PROCESSING
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_DIGITAL_SIGNAL_PROCESSING"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_DIGITAL_SIGNAL_PROCESSING"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_DIGITAL_SIGNAL_PROCESSING"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_DIGITAL_SIGNAL_PROCESSING"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_DIGITAL_SIGNAL_PROCESSING"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS INTEGRATED_CIRCUIT
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_INTEGRATED_CIRCUIT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_INTEGRATED_CIRCUIT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_INTEGRATED_CIRCUIT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_INTEGRATED_CIRCUIT"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_INTEGRATED_CIRCUIT"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS PRINCIPAL_OF_COMMUNICATION
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_PRINCIPAL_OF_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_PRINCIPAL_OF_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_PRINCIPAL_OF_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_PRINCIPAL_OF_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_PRINCIPAL_OF_COMMUNICATION"></string>


    ECE3YEAR SYLLABUS CONTROL_SYSTEM_1
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE3_CONTROL_SYSTEM_1"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE3_CONTROL_SYSTEM_1"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE3_CONTROL_SYSTEM_1"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE3_CONTROL_SYSTEM_1"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE3_CONTROL_SYSTEM_1"></string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS HUMAN_VALUES
    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_HUMAN_VALUES">Course Introduction - Need, Basic Guidelines, Content and Process for Value Education
 Understanding the need, basic guidelines, content and process for Value Education, Self-Exploration–what is it? - its content and process; ‘Natural Acceptance’ and  Experiential Validation- as the mechanism for self exploration, Continuous Happiness and Prosperity- A look at basic Human Aspirations, Right understanding, Relationship and Physical Facilities- the basic requirements for fulfillment of aspirations of every human being with their correct priority, Understanding Happiness and Prosperity correctly- A critical appraisal of the current scenario, Method to fulfill  the above human aspirations: understanding and living in harmony at various levels.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Human Being - Harmony in Myself
 Understanding human being as a co-existence of the sentient ‘I’ and the material ‘Body’, Understanding the needs of Self (‘I’) and ‘Body’ - Sukh and Suvidha, Understanding the Body as an instrument of ‘I’ (I being the doer, seer and enjoyer), Understanding the characteristics and activities of ‘I’ and harmony in ‘I’, Understanding the harmony of I with the Body: Sanyam and Swasthya; correct appraisal of Physical needs, meaning of Prosperity in detail,  Programs to  ensure Sanyam and Swasthya. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Family and Society- Harmony in Human-Human Relationship
 Understanding harmony in the Family- the basic unit of human interaction , Understanding values in human-human relationship; meaning of Nyaya and program for its fulfillment to ensure Ubhay-tripti; Trust (Vishwas) and Respect (Samman) as the foundational values of relationship, Understanding the meaning of Vishwas; Difference between intention and competence, Understanding the meaning of Samman, Difference between respect and differentiation; the other salient values in relationship, Understanding the harmony in the society (society being an extension of family): Samadhan, Samridhi, Abhay, Sah-astitva as comprehensive Human Goals, Visualizing a universal harmonious order in society- Undivided Society (AkhandSamaj), Universal Order (SarvabhaumVyawastha )- from family to world family!.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Nature and Existence - Whole existence as Co-existence
 Understanding the harmony in the Nature, Interconnectedness and mutual fulfillment among the four orders of nature- recyclability and self-regulation in nature,  Understanding Existence as Co-existence (Sah-astitva) of mutually interacting units in all-pervasive space, Holistic perception of harmony at all levels of existence.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_HUMAN_VALUES">Implications of the above Holistic Understanding of Harmony on Professional Ethics
 Natural acceptance of human values, Definitiveness of Ethical  Human Conduct, Basis for Humanistic Education, Humanistic Constitution and Humanistic Universal Order, Competence in Professional Ethics: a) Ability to utilize the professional competence for augmenting universal human order,  b) Ability to identify the scope and characteristics of people-friendly and eco-friendly </string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION

    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"> Fundamentals of Technical Communication:

Technical Communication: Features; Distinction between General and Technical
Communication; Language as a tool of Communication; Dimensions of Communication:
Reading and comprehension; Technical writing: sentences; Paragraph; Technical style: Definition,
types and Methods; The flow of Communication: Downward; upward, Lateral or Horizontal;
Barriers to Communication.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION">Forms of Technical Communication:

Technical Report: Definition and importance; Thesis/Project writing: structure and importance;
synopsis writing: Methods; Technical research Paper writing: Methods and style; Seminar and
Conference paper writing; Expert Technical Lecture: Theme clarity; Analysis and Findings; 7 Cs
of effective business writing: concreteness, completeness, clarity, conciseness, courtesy,
correctness, consideration, C.V./Resume writing; Technical Proposal: Types, Structure and Draft.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION">Technical Presentation: Strategies and Techniques
Presentation: Forms; interpersonal Communication; Class room presentation; style; method;
Individual conferencing: essentials: Public Speaking: method; Techniques: Clarity of substance;
emotion; Humour; Modes of Presentation; Overcoming Stage Fear; Audience Analysis and
retention of audience interest; Methods of Presentation: Interpersonal; Impersonal; Audience
Participation: Quizzes and Interjections.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION">Technical Communication Skills:
Interview skills; Group Discussion: Objective and Method; Seminar/Conferences Presentation
skills: Focus; Content; Style; Argumentation skills: Devices: Analysis; Cohesion and Emphasis;
Critical thinking; Nuances: Exposition narration and Description; effective business
communication competence: Grammatical; Discourse competence: combination of expression and
conclusion; Socio-linguistic competence: Strategic competence: Solution of communication
problems with verbal and non verbal means.</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION">Dimensions of Oral Communication and Voice Dynamics:
Code and Content; Stimulus and Response; Encoding process; Decoding process; Pronunciation
Etiquette; Syllables; Vowel sounds; Consonant sounds; Tone: Rising tone; Falling Tone; Flow in
Speaking; Speaking with a purpose; Speech and personality; Professional Personality Attributes:
Empathy; Considerateness; Leadership; Competence.
</string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS AUTOMETA
    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_AUTOMETA">Basic Concepts and Automata Theory: Introduction to Theory of Computation- Automata, Computability and Complexity, Alphabet, Symbol, String, Formal Languages, Deterministic Finite Automaton (DFA)- Definition, Representation, Acceptability of a String and Language, Non Deterministic Finite Automaton (NFA), Equivalence of DFA and NFA, NFA with ε-Transition, Equivalence of NFA’s with and without ε-Transition, Finite Automata with output- Moore Machine, Mealy Machine, Equivalence of Moore and Mealy Machine, Minimization of Finite Automata, Myhill-Nerode Theorem, Simulation of DFA and NFA</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_AUTOMETA">Regular Expressions and Languages: Regular Expressions, Transition Graph, Kleen’s Theorem, Finite Automata and Regular Expression- Arden’s theorem, Algebraic Method Using Arden’s Theorem, Regular and Non-Regular Languages- Closure properties of Regular Languages, Pigeonhole Principle, Pumping Lemma, Application of Pumping Lemma, Decidability- Decision properties, Finite Automata and Regular Languages, Regular Languages and Computers, Simulation of Transition Graph and Regular language. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_AUTOMETA"> Regular and Non-Regular Grammars: Context Free Grammar(CFG)-Definition, Derivations, Languages, Derivation Trees and Ambiguity, Regular Grammars-Right Linear and Left Linear grammars, Conversion of FA into CFG and Regular grammar into FA, Simplification of CFG, Normal Forms- Chomsky Normal Form(CNF), Greibach Normal Form (GNF), Chomsky Hierarchy, Programming problems based on the properties of CFGs. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_AUTOMETA">Push Down Automata and Properties of Context Free Languages: Nondeterministic Pushdown Automata (NPDA)- Definition, Moves, A Language Accepted by NPDA, Deterministic Pushdown Automata(DPDA) and Deterministic Context free Languages(DCFL), Pushdown Automata for Context Free Languages, Context Free grammars for Pushdown Automata, Two stack Pushdown Automata, Pumping Lemma for CFL, Closure properties of CFL, Decision Problems of CFL, Programming problems based on the properties of CFLs. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_AUTOMETA">Turing Machines and Recursive Function Theory : Basic Turing Machine Model, Representation of Turing Machines, Language Acceptability of Turing Machines, Techniques for Turing Machine Construction, Modifications of Turing Machine, Turing Machine as Computer of Integer Functions, Universal Turing machine, Linear Bounded Automata, Church’s Thesis, Recursive and Recursively Enumerable language, Halting Problem, Post’s Correspondance Problem, Introduction to Recursive Function Theory. </string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS COA
    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_COA">Introduction: Functional units of digital system and their interconnections, buses, bus architecture, types of buses and bus arbitration. Register, bus and memory transfer.  Processor organization, general registers organization, stack organization and addressing modes. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_COA">Arithmetic and logic unit: Look ahead carries adders. Multiplication: Signed operand multiplication, Booths algorithm and array multiplier. Division and logic operations. Floating point arithmetic operation, Arithmetic and logic unit design. IEEE Standard for Floating Point Numbers </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_COA">Control Unit: Instruction types, formats, instruction cycles and sub cycles (fetch and execute etc), micro operations, execution of a complete instruction. Program Control, Reduced Instruction Set Computer, Pipelining. Hardwire and micro programmed control: micro programme sequencing, concept of horizontal and vertical microprogramming. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_COA">Memory: Basic concept and hierarchy, semiconductor RAM memories, 2D and 2 1/2D memory organization. ROM memories.  Cache memories: concept and design issues and performance, address mapping and replacement Auxiliary memories: magnetic disk, magnetic tape and optical disks Virtual memory: concept implementation. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_COA">Input / Output: Peripheral devices, I/O interface, I/O ports, Interrupts: interrupt hardware, types of interrupts and exceptions.  Modes of Data Transfer: Programmed I/O, interrupt initiated I/O and Direct Memory Access., I/O channels and processors.  Serial Communication: Synchronous and asynchronous communication, standard communication interfaces. </string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS OS
    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_OS">Introduction : Operating system and functions, Classification of Operating systems- Batch, Interactive, Time sharing, Real Time System, Multiprocessor Systems, Multiuser Systems, Multiprocess Systems, Multithreaded Systems, Operating System Structure- Layered structure, System Components, Operating System services, Reentrant Kernels, Monolithic and Microkernel Systems.  </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_OS">Concurrent Processes: Process Concept, Principle of Concurrency, Producer / Consumer Problem, Mutual Exclusion, Critical Section Problem, Dekker’s solution, Peterson’s solution, Semaphores, Test and Set operation; Classical Problem in Concurrency- Dining Philosopher Problem, Sleeping Barber Problem; Inter Process Communication models and Schemes, Process generation</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_OS">CPU Scheduling: Scheduling Concepts, Performance Criteria, Process States, Process Transition Diagram, Schedulers, Process Control Block (PCB), Process address space, Process identification information, Threads and their management, Scheduling Algorithms, Multiprocessor Scheduling. Deadlock: System model, Deadlock characterization, Prevention, Avoidance and detection, Recovery from deadlock. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_OS">Memory Management: Basic bare machine, Resident monitor, Multiprogramming with fixed partitions, Multiprogramming with variable partitions, Protection schemes, Paging, Segmentation, Paged segmentation, Virtual memory concepts, Demand paging, Performance of demand paging, Page replacement algorithms, Thrashing, Cache memory organization, Locality of reference.  </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_OS">I/O Management and Disk Scheduling: I/O devices, and I/O subsystems, I/O buffering, Disk storage and disk scheduling, RAID. File System: File concept, File organization and access mechanism, File directories, and File sharing, File system implementation issues, File system protection and security. </string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS DSTL
    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_DSTL">Set Theory: Introduction, Combination of sets, Multisets, Ordered pairs. Proofs of some general identities on sets.  Relations: Definition, Operations on relations, Properties of relations, Composite Relations, Equality of relations, Recursive definition of relation, Order of relations.  Functions: Definition, Classification of functions, Operations on functions, Recursively defined functions. Growth of Functions.   Natural Numbers: Introduction, Mathematical Induction, Variants of Induction, Induction with Nonzero Base cases. Proof Methods, Proof by counter – example, Proof by contradiction</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_DSTL">Algebraic Structures: Definition, Groups, Subgroups and order, Cyclic Groups, Cosets, Lagrange\'s theorem, Normal Subgroups, Permutation and Symmetric groups, Group Homomorphisms, Definition and elementary properties of Rings and Fields.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_DSTL">Lattices: Definition, Properties of lattices – Bounded, Complemented, Modular and Complete lattice.  Boolean Algebra: Introduction, Axioms and Theorems of Boolean algebra, Algebraic manipulation of Boolean expressions. Simplification of Boolean Functions, Karnaugh maps, Logic gates, Digital circuits and Boolean algebra. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_DSTL">Propositional Logic: Proposition, well formed formula, Truth tables, Tautology, Satisfiability, Contradiction, Algebra of proposition, Theory of Inference. (8)    Predicate Logic: First order predicate, well formed formula of predicate, quantifiers, Inference theory of predicate logic. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_DSTL">Trees: Definition, Binary tree, Binary tree traversal, Binary search tree.   Graphs: Definition and terminology, Representation of graphs, Multigraphs, Bipartite graphs, Planar graphs, Isomorphism and Homeomorphism of graphs, Euler and Hamiltonian paths, Graph coloring, Recurrence Relation and Generating function: Recursive definition of functions, Recursive algorithms, Method of solving recurrences.   Combinatorics: Introduction, Counting Techniques, Pigeonhole Principle </string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS ENGG_SCIENCE
    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_ENGG_SCIENCE">Introduction to Soft Computing,  ARTIFICIAL NEURAL NETWORKS Basic concepts - Single layer perception - Multilayer Perception - Supervised and Unsupervised learning – Back propagation networks - Kohnen self-organizing networks - Hopfield network. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_ENGG_SCIENCE">FUZZY SYSTEMS  Fuzzy sets, Fuzzy Relations and Fuzzy reasoning, Fuzzy functions - Decomposition - Fuzzy automata and languages - Fuzzy control methods - Fuzzy decision making.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_ENGG_SCIENCE">NEURO - FUZZY MODELING  Adaptive networks based Fuzzy interface systems - Classification and Regression Trees - Data  clustering algorithms - Rule based structure identification - Neuro-Fuzzy controls - Simulated annealing – Evolutionary computation </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_ENGG_SCIENCE">GENETIC ALGORITHMS  Survival of the Fittest - Fitness Computations - Cross over - Mutation - Reproduction - Rank method - Rank space method. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_ENGG_SCIENCE">APPLICATION OF SOFT COMPUTING  Optimiation of traveling salesman problem using Genetic Algorithm, Genetic algorithm based Internet Search Techniques, Soft computing based hybrid fuzzy controller, Introduction to MATLAB Environment for Soft computing Techniques. </string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS DS
    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_DS">Introduction: Basic Terminology, Elementary Data Organization, Built in Data Types in C. Algorithm, Efficiency of an Algorithm, Time and Space Complexity, Asymptotic notations: Big Oh, Big Theta and Big Omega, Time-Space trade-off. Abstract Data Types (ADT)   Arrays: Definition, Single and Multidimensional Arrays, Representation of Arrays: Row Major Order, and Column Major Order, Derivation of Index Formulae for 1-D,2-D,3-D and n-D Array Application of arrays, Sparse Matrices and their representations.   Linked lists: Array Implementation and Pointer Implementation of Singly Linked Lists, Doubly Linked List, Circularly Linked List, Operations on a Linked List. Insertion, Deletion, Traversal, Polynomial Representation and Addition Subtraction and Multiplications of Single variable and Two variables Polynomial. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_DS">Stacks: Abstract Data Type, Primitive Stack operations: Push and Pop, Array and Linked Implementation of Stack in C, Application of stack: Prefix and Postfix Expressions, Evaluation of postfix expression, Iteration and Recursion- Principles of recursion, Tail recursion, Removal of recursion Problem solving using iteration and recursion with examples such as binary search, Fibonacci numbers, and Hanoi towers. Tradeoffs between iteration and recursion. Queues: Operations on Queue: Create, Add, Delete, Full and Empty, Circular queues, Array and linked implementation of queues in C, Dequeue and Priority Queue.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_DS">Searching: Concept of Searching, Sequential search, Index Sequential Search, Binary Search. Concept of Hashing and Collision resolution Techniques used in Hashing. Sorting: Insertion Sort, Selection, Bubble Sort, Quick Sort, Merge Sort, Heap Sort and Radix Sort.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_DS">Graphs: Terminology used with Graph, Data Structure for Graph Representations: Adjacency Matrices, Adjacency List, Adjacency. Graph Traversal: Depth First Search and Breadth First Search, Connected Component, Spanning Trees, Minimum Cost Spanning Trees: Prims and Kruskal algorithm. Transitive Closure and Shortest Path algorithm: Warshal Algorithm and Dijikstra Algorithm. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_DS">Trees: Basic terminology used with Tree, Binary Trees, Binary Tree Representation: Array Representation and Pointer(Linked List) Representation, Binary Search Tree, Strictly Binary Tree ,Complete Binary Tree . A Extended Binary Trees, Tree Traversal algorithms: Inorder, Preorder and Postorder, Constructing Binary Tree from given Tree Traversal, Operation of Insertation , Deletion, Searching and Modification of data  in Binary Search . Threaded Binary trees, Traversing Threaded Binary trees.  Huffman coding using Binary Tree. Concept and Basic Operations for  AVL Tree , B Tree and Binary Heaps </string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS MATH3
    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_MATH3">Laplace transform, Existence theorem, Laplace transforms of derivatives and integrals, Initial and final value theorems, Unit step function, Dirac- delta function, Laplace transform of periodic function, Inverse Laplace transform, Convolution theorem, Application to solve simple linear and simultaneous differential equations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_MATH3">Integral Transforms
Fourier integral, Fourier Transform , Complex Fourier transform, Inverse Transforms, Convolution Theorems, Fourier sine and cosine transform, Applications of Fourier transform to simple one dimensional heat transfer equations, wave equations and Laplace equations,  Z- Transform and its application to solve difference equations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_MATH3">Formal Logic ,Group, Ring and Field:  Introduction to First order logic, Proposition, Algebra of Proposition, Logical connectives, Tautologies, contradictions and contingency, Logical implication, Argument, Normal form, Rules of inferences, semi group, Monoid Group, Group, Cosets, Lagrange’s theorem , Congruence relation ,  Cyclic and permutation groups, Properties of groups,  Rings and Fields (definition, examples and standard results only) </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_MATH3">Set, Relation, function and Counting Techniques - Introduction of Sets, Relation and Function, Methods of Proof, Mathematical Induction, Strong Mathematical Induction, Discrete numeric function and Generating functions, recurrence relations and their solution , Pigeonhole principle. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_MATH3">Lattices and Boolean Algebra: Introduction, Partially ordered sets, Hasse Diagram, Maximal and Minimal element, Upper and Lower bounds, Isomorphic ordered sets, Lattices, Bounded Lattices and , Distributive Lattices.
Duality, Boolean Algebras as Lattices, Minimization of Boolean Expressions, prime Implicants, Logic Gates and Circuits, Truth Table, Boolean Functions, Karnaugh Maps. </string>


    CS2YEAR SYLLABUS MICROPROCESSOR
    <string name="UNIT1_CS2_MICROPROCESSOR">Microprocessor evolution and types, microprocessor architecture and operation of its components, addressing modes, interrupts, data transfer schemes, instruction and data flow, timer and timing diagram, Interfacing devices. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CS2_MICROPROCESSOR">Pin diagram and internal architecture of 8085 microprocessor, registers, ALU, Control and status, interrupt and machine cycle. Instruction sets. Addressing modes. Instruction formats Instruction Classification: data transfer, arithmetic operations, logical operations, branching operations, machine control and assembler directives. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CS2_MICROPROCESSOR">Architecture of 8086 microprocessor: register organization, bus interface unit, execution unit, memory addressing, and memory segmentation. Operating modes. Instruction sets, instruction format, Types of instructions. Interrupts: hardware and software interrupts. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CS2_MICROPROCESSOR">Assembly language programming based on intel 8085/8086. Instructions, data transfer, arithmetic, logic, branch operations, looping, counting, indexing, programming techniques, counters and time delays, stacks and subroutines, conditional call and return instructions</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CS2_MICROPROCESSOR">Peripheral Devices: 8237 DMA Controller, 8255 programmable peripheral interface, 8253/8254programmable timer/counter, 8259 programmable interrupt controller, 8251 USART and RS232C. </string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS HUMAN_VALUES
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_HUMAN_VALUES">Course Introduction - Need, Basic Guidelines, Content and Process for Value Education
 Understanding the need, basic guidelines, content and process for Value Education, Self-Exploration–what is it? - its content and process; ‘Natural Acceptance’ and  Experiential Validation- as the mechanism for self exploration, Continuous Happiness and Prosperity- A look at basic Human Aspirations, Right understanding, Relationship and Physical Facilities- the basic requirements for fulfillment of aspirations of every human being with their correct priority, Understanding Happiness and Prosperity correctly- A critical appraisal of the current scenario, Method to fulfill  the above human aspirations: understanding and living in harmony at various levels.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Human Being - Harmony in Myself
 Understanding human being as a co-existence of the sentient ‘I’ and the material ‘Body’, Understanding the needs of Self (‘I’) and ‘Body’ - Sukh and Suvidha, Understanding the Body as an instrument of ‘I’ (I being the doer, seer and enjoyer), Understanding the characteristics and activities of ‘I’ and harmony in ‘I’, Understanding the harmony of I with the Body: Sanyam and Swasthya; correct appraisal of Physical needs, meaning of Prosperity in detail,  Programs to  ensure Sanyam and Swasthya. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Family and Society- Harmony in Human-Human Relationship
 Understanding harmony in the Family- the basic unit of human interaction , Understanding values in human-human relationship; meaning of Nyaya and program for its fulfillment to ensure Ubhay-tripti; Trust (Vishwas) and Respect (Samman) as the foundational values of relationship, Understanding the meaning of Vishwas; Difference between intention and competence, Understanding the meaning of Samman, Difference between respect and differentiation; the other salient values in relationship, Understanding the harmony in the society (society being an extension of family): Samadhan, Samridhi, Abhay, Sah-astitva as comprehensive Human Goals, Visualizing a universal harmonious order in society- Undivided Society (AkhandSamaj), Universal Order (SarvabhaumVyawastha )- from family to world family!.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Nature and Existence - Whole existence as Co-existence
 Understanding the harmony in the Nature, Interconnectedness and mutual fulfillment among the four orders of nature- recyclability and self-regulation in nature,  Understanding Existence as Co-existence (Sah-astitva) of mutually interacting units in all-pervasive space, Holistic perception of harmony at all levels of existence.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_HUMAN_VALUES">Implications of the above Holistic Understanding of Harmony on Professional Ethics
 Natural acceptance of human values, Definitiveness of Ethical  Human Conduct, Basis for Humanistic Education, Humanistic Constitution and Humanistic Universal Order, Competence in Professional Ethics: a) Ability to utilize the professional competence for augmenting universal human order,  b) Ability to identify the scope and characteristics of people-friendly and eco-friendly </string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS SCIENCE_COURCE
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_SCIENCE_COURCE">Phase Diagrams: Solid solutions – Hume Rothery’s rules – the phase rule – single component system – one-component system of iron – binary phase diagrams – isomorphous systems – the tie-line rule – the lever rule – application to isomorphous system – eutectic phase diagram – peritectic phase diagram – other invariant reactions – free energy composition curves for binary systems – microstructural change during cooling.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_SCIENCE_COURCE">Ferrous Alloys: The iron-carbon equilibrium diagram – phases, invariant reactions – microstructure of slowly cooled steels – eutectoid steel, hypo and hypereutectoid steels – effect of alloying elements on the Fe-C system – diffusion in solids – Fick’s laws – phase transformations – T-T-T-diagram for eutectoid steel – pearlitic, baintic and martensitic transformations – tempering of martensite – steels – stainless steels – cast irons. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_SCIENCE_COURCE">Mechanical Properties: Tensile test – plastic deformation mechanisms – slip and twinning – role of dislocations in slip – strengthening methods – strain hardening – refinement of the grain size – solid solution strengthening – precipitation hardening – creep resistance – creep curves – mechanisms of creep – creep-resistant materials – fracture – the Griffith criterion – critical stress intensity factor and its determination – fatigue failure – fatigue tests – methods of increasing fatigue life – hardness – Rockwell and Brinell hardness – Knoop and Vickers microhardness. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_SCIENCE_COURCE">Magnetic, Dielectric And Superconducting Materials: Ferromagnetism – domain theory – types of energy – hysteresis – hard and soft magnetic materials – ferrites – dielectric materials – types of polarization – Langevin-Debye equation – frequency effects on polarization – dielectric breakdown – insulating materials – Ferroelectric materials – superconducting materials and their properties. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_SCIENCE_COURCE">New Materials: Ceramics – types and applications – composites: classification, role of matrix and reinforcement, processing of fiber reinforced plastics – metallic glasses: types , glass forming ability of alloys, melt spinning process, applications – shape memory alloys: phases, shape memory effect, pseudoelastic effect, NiTi alloy, applications – nanomaterials: preparation (bottom up and top down approaches), properties and applications – carbon nanotubes: types. </string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"> Fundamentals of Technical Communication:

Technical Communication: Features; Distinction between General and Technical
Communication; Language as a tool of Communication; Dimensions of Communication:
Reading and comprehension; Technical writing: sentences; Paragraph; Technical style: Definition,
types and Methods; The flow of Communication: Downward; upward, Lateral or Horizontal;
Barriers to Communication.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION">Forms of Technical Communication:

Technical Report: Definition and importance; Thesis/Project writing: structure and importance;
synopsis writing: Methods; Technical research Paper writing: Methods and style; Seminar and
Conference paper writing; Expert Technical Lecture: Theme clarity; Analysis and Findings; 7 Cs
of effective business writing: concreteness, completeness, clarity, conciseness, courtesy,
correctness, consideration, C.V./Resume writing; Technical Proposal: Types, Structure and Draft.
</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION">Technical Presentation: Strategies and Techniques
Presentation: Forms; interpersonal Communication; Class room presentation; style; method;
Individual conferencing: essentials: Public Speaking: method; Techniques: Clarity of substance;
emotion; Humour; Modes of Presentation; Overcoming Stage Fear; Audience Analysis and
retention of audience interest; Methods of Presentation: Interpersonal; Impersonal; Audience
Participation: Quizzes and Interjections.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION">Technical Communication Skills:
Interview skills; Group Discussion: Objective and Method; Seminar/Conferences Presentation
skills: Focus; Content; Style; Argumentation skills: Devices: Analysis; Cohesion and Emphasis;
Critical thinking; Nuances: Exposition narration and Description; effective business
communication competence: Grammatical; Discourse competence: combination of expression and
conclusion; Socio-linguistic competence: Strategic competence: Solution of communication
problems with verbal and non verbal means.</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION">Dimensions of Oral Communication and Voice Dynamics:
Code and Content; Stimulus and Response; Encoding process; Decoding process; Pronunciation
Etiquette; Syllables; Vowel sounds; Consonant sounds; Tone: Rising tone; Falling Tone; Flow in
Speaking; Speaking with a purpose; Speech and personality; Professional Personality Attributes:
Empathy; Considerateness; Leadership; Competence.
</string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS MATH3
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_MATH3">Laplace transform, Existence theorem, Laplace transforms of derivatives and integrals, Initial and final value theorems, Unit step function, Dirac- delta function, Laplace transform of periodic function, Inverse Laplace transform, Convolution theorem, Application to solve simple linear and simultaneous differential equations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_MATH3">Integral Transforms
Fourier integral, Fourier Transform , Complex Fourier transform, Inverse Transforms, Convolution Theorems, Fourier sine and cosine transform, Applications of Fourier transform to simple one dimensional heat transfer equations, wave equations and Laplace equations,  Z- Transform and its application to solve difference equations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_MATH3">Formal Logic ,Group, Ring and Field:  Introduction to First order logic, Proposition, Algebra of Proposition, Logical connectives, Tautologies, contradictions and contingency, Logical implication, Argument, Normal form, Rules of inferences, semi group, Monoid Group, Group, Cosets, Lagrange’s theorem , Congruence relation ,  Cyclic and permutation groups, Properties of groups,  Rings and Fields (definition, examples and standard results only) </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_MATH3">Set, Relation, function and Counting Techniques - Introduction of Sets, Relation and Function, Methods of Proof, Mathematical Induction, Strong Mathematical Induction, Discrete numeric function and Generating functions, recurrence relations and their solution , Pigeonhole principle. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_MATH3">Lattices and Boolean Algebra: Introduction, Partially ordered sets, Hasse Diagram, Maximal and Minimal element, Upper and Lower bounds, Isomorphic ordered sets, Lattices, Bounded Lattices and , Distributive Lattices.
Duality, Boolean Algebras as Lattices, Minimization of Boolean Expressions, prime Implicants, Logic Gates and Circuits, Truth Table, Boolean Functions, Karnaugh Maps. </string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS THERMODYNAMICS
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_THERMODYNAMICS">Review of Fundamental Concepts and Definitions:  Introduction- Basic Concepts: System, ControlVolume, Surrounding, Boundaries, Universe, Types of Systems, Macroscopic and Microscopicviewpoints, Concept of Continuum, Thermodynamic Equilibrium, State, Property, Process, Exact and Inexact Differentials, Cycle Reversibility Quasi – static Process, Irreversible Process, Causes of Irreversibility Energy and its forms, Work and heat (sign convention), Gas laws, Ideal gas, Real gas, Law of corresponding states, Property of mixture of gases, electrical, magnetic,gravitational, spring and shaft work. Zeroth law of thermodynamics:Concept of Temperature and its’ measurement, Temperature scales.  First law of thermodynamics:  First Law for Flow Processes - Derivation of general energy equation for a control volume;Steady state steady flow processes including throttling; Examples of steady flow devices;Unsteady processes; examples of steady and unsteady I law applications for system andcontrol volume. Limitations of first law of thermodynamics, PMM-I. Steady flow systems and their analysis, Steady flow energy equation, Boilers, Condensers, Turbine, Throttling process, Pumps etc.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_THERMODYNAMICS">Second law of thermodynamics:  Thermal reservoirs, Energy conversion, Heat engines, Efficiency, Reversed heat engine, Heat pump, Refrigerator, Coefficient of Performance, Kelvin Planck and Clausius statement of second law of thermodynamics, Equivalence of the two statements. Reversible and irreversible processes, Carnot cycle and Carnot engine, Carnot theorem and it’s corollaries, Thermodynamic Temperature Scale, PMM-II.  Entropy: Clausius inequality, Concept of Entropy, Entropy change of pure substance in different thermodynamic processes, Tds equation, Principle of entropy increase, T-S diagram, Statement of the third law of thermodynamics. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_THERMODYNAMICS">Availability and Irreversibility:  Available and unavailable energy, Availability and Irreversibility, Second law efficiency, Helmholtz and Gibb’s function.  Thermodynamic relations: Conditions for exact differentials. Maxwell relations, Clapeyron equation, Joule-Thompson coefficient and Inversion curve. Coefficient of volume expansion, Adiabatic and Isothermal compressibility.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_THERMODYNAMICS">Pure substance, Property of Pure Substance (steam), Triple point, Critical point, Saturation states, Subcooled liquid state, Superheated vapour state, Phase transformation process of water, Graphical representation of pressure, volume and temperature, P-T, P-V and P-h diagrams, T-S and H-S diagrams, use of property diagram, Steam-Tables and Moller chart, Dryness factor and it’s measurement, processes involving steam in closed and open systems. Simple Rankine cycle.  Air-water vapour mixture and Psychrometry: Psychometric terms and their definitions, Psychometric chart, Different Psychometric processes and their representation on Psychometric chart.  </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_THERMODYNAMICS">Refrigeration Cycles:  Reversed Carnot Cycle for gas and vapour. Refrigeration capacity, unit of refrigeration.Air Refrigeration cycles; Reversed Brayton Cycle and Bell Coleman Cycle. Vapour compression refrigeration cycle; simple saturated cycle and actual vapour compression refrigeration cycle. Analysis of cycles, effect of superheating, sub-cooling and change in evaporator and condenser pressure on performance of vapour compression refrigeration cycle. Refrigerants; their classification and desirable properties. Vapour absorption refrigeration system. </string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS FLUID_MECHANICS
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_FLUID_MECHANICS">Definition of fluid, Newton’s law of viscosity, Units and dimensions-Properties of fluids,mass density, specific volume, specific gravity, viscosity, compressibility and surfacetension, Incompressible flow, Bernoulli’s equation and its applications - Pitot tube, orifice meter, venturi meter and bend meter, notches and weirs, momentum equation and its application to pipe bends. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_FLUID_MECHANICS">Continuum and free molecular flows. Steady and unsteady, uniform and non-uniform, laminar and turbulent flows, rotational and irrotational flows, compressible and incompressible flows, subsonic, sonic and supersonic flows, sub-critical, critical and supercritical flows, one, two- and threedimensional flows, streamlines, continuity equation for 3D and 1D flows, circulation, stream function and velocity potential. Buckingham’s Pi theorem, important dimensionless numbers and their significance.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_FLUID_MECHANICS">Equation of motion for laminar flow through pipes, turbulent flow, isotropic, homogenous turbulence, scale and intensity of turbulence, measurement of turbulence, eddy viscosity, resistance to flow, minor losses, pipe in series and parallel, power transmission through a pipe, siphon, water hammer, three reservoir problems and pipe networks. Boundary layer thickness, boundary layer over a flat plate, laminar boundary layer, application of momentum equation, turbulent boundary layer, laminar sublayer, separation and its control, Drag and lift, drag on a sphere, a two-dimensional cylinder, and an aerofoil, Magnus effect. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_FLUID_MECHANICS">Introduction to hydrodynamic thrust of jet on a fixed and moving surface, Classification of turbines, Impulse turbines, Constructional details, Velocity triangles, Power and efficiency calculations, Governing of Pelton wheel. Francis and Kaplan turbines, Constructional details, Velocity triangles, Power and efficiency Principles of similarity, Unit and specific speed, Performance characteristics, Selection of water turbines.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_FLUID_MECHANICS">Classifications of centrifugal pumps, Vector diagram, Work done by impellor, Efficiencies of centrifugal pumps, Specific speed, Cavitation and separation, Performance characteristics. Reciprocating pump theory, Slip, Indicator diagram, Effect of acceleration, air vessels, Comparison of centrifugal and reciprocating pumps, Performance characteristics</string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS MATERIALS
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_MATERIALS">Crystal Structure: Unit cells, Metallic crystal structures, Ceramics. Imperfection in solids:Point, line, interfacial and volume defects; dislocation strengthening mechanisms and slipsystems, critically resolved shear stress. Mechanical Property measurement: Tensile, compression and torsion tests; Young’smodulus, relations between true and engineering stress-strain curves, generalized Hooke’slaw, yielding and yield strength, ductility, resilience, toughness and elastic recovery;Hardness: Rockwell, Brinell and Vickers and their relation to strength. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_MATERIALS">Static failure theories: Ductile and brittle failure mechanisms, Tresca, Von-mises, Maximumnormal stress, Mohr-Coulomb and Modified Mohr-Coulomb; Fracture mechanics:Introduction to Stressintensity factor approach and Griffith criterion. Fatigue failure: Highcycle fatigue, Stress-life approach, SN curve, endurance and fatigue limits, effects of meanstress using the Modified Goodman diagram; Fracture with fatigue, Introduction to non-destructive testing (NDT). </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_MATERIALS">Alloys, substitutional and interstitial solid solutions- Phase diagrams: Interpretation of binaryphase diagrams and microstructure development; eutectic, peritectic, peritectoid and monotectic reactions. Iron Iron-carbide phase diagram and microstructural aspects ofledeburite, austenite, ferrite and cementite, cast iron. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_MATERIALS">Heat treatment of Steel: Annealing, tempering, normalising and spheroidising, isothermaltransformation diagrams for Fe-C alloys and microstructure development. Continuouscooling curves and interpretation of final microstructures and properties- austempering,martempering, case hardening, carburizing, nitriding, cyaniding, carbo-nitriding, flame andinduction hardening, vacuum and plasma hardening. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_MATERIALS">Alloying of steel, properties of stainless steel and tool steels, maraging steels- cast irons;grey, white, malleable and spheroidal cast irons- copper and copper alloys; brass, bronze andcupro-nickel; Aluminium and Al-Cu – Mg alloys- Nickel based superalloys and Titaniumalloys. </string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS APPLIED_THERMODYNAMICS
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_APPLIED_THERMODYNAMICS">Introduction to solid, liquid and gaseous fuels– Stoichiometry, exhaust gas analysis- First lawanalysis of combustion reactions- Heat calculations using enthalpy tables- Adiabatic flametemperature- Chemical equilibrium and equilibrium composition calculations using freeenergy. Introduction and Otto, Diesel and Dual cycles. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_APPLIED_THERMODYNAMICS">Vapour Power cycles:  Vapor power cycles Rankine cycle with superheat, reheat and regeneration, exergy analysis. Rankine cycle, effect of pressure and temperature on Rankine cycle, Reheat cycle, Regenerative cycle, Feed water heaters, Binary vapour cycle, Combined cycles, Cogeneration.  Fuels and Combustion: Combustion analysis, heating values, air requirement, Air/Fuel ratio, standard heat of reaction and effect of temperature on standard heat of reaction, heat of formation, Adiabatic flame temperature. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_APPLIED_THERMODYNAMICS">Boilers: Classifications and working of boilers, boiler mountings and accessories, Draught and its calculations, air pre-heater, feed water heater, super heater. Boiler efficiency, Equivalent evaporation. Boiler trial and heat balance.  Condenser: Classification of condenser, air leakage, condenser performance parameters</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_APPLIED_THERMODYNAMICS">Steam and Gas Nozzles: Flow through Convergent and convergent-divergent nozzles, variation of velocity, area and specific volume, choked flow, throat area, Nozzle efficiency, Off design operation of nozzle, Shock waves stationary normal shock waves, Effect of friction on nozzle, Super saturated flow.  Steam Turbines: Classification of steam turbine, Impulse and Reaction turbines, Staging, Stage and Overall efficiency, reheat factor, Bleeding, Velocity diagram of simple and compound multistage impulse and reaction turbines and related calculations, work done, efficiencies of reaction, Impulse reaction turbines, state point locus, Losses in steam turbines, Governing of turbines, Comparison with steam engine.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_APPLIED_THERMODYNAMICS">Gas Turbine: Gas turbine classification, Brayton cycle, Principles of gas turbine, Gas turbine cycles with intercooling, reheat and regeneration and their combinations, Stage efficiency, Polytropic efficiency. Deviation of actual cycles from ideal cycles.  Jet Propulsion: Introduction to the principles of jet propulsion, Turbojet and turboprop engines andtheir processes, Principle of rocket propulsion, Introduction to Rocket Engine. Reciprocating compressors, staging of reciprocating compressors, optimal stage pressureratio, effect of intercooling, minimum work for multistage reciprocating compressors. </string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS MANUFACTURING_PROCESS
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_MANUFACTURING_PROCESS">Conventional Manufacturing processes: Casting and moulding: Metal casting processes and equipment, Heat transfer andsolidification, shrinkage, riser design, casting defects and residual stresses.Introduction to bulk and sheet metal forming, plastic deformation and yield criteria;fundamentals of hot and cold working processes; load estimation for bulk forming (forging,rolling, extrusion, drawing) and sheet forming (shearing, deep drawing, bending) principlesof powder metallurgy. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_MANUFACTURING_PROCESS">Metal cutting: Single and multi-point cutting; Orthogonal cutting, various force components:Chip formation, Tool wear and tool life, Surface finish and integrity, Machinability, cutting tool materials, cutting fluids, Coating; Turning, Drilling, Milling and finishing processes,Introduction to CNC machining.Additive manufacturing: Rapid prototyping and rapid toolingJoining/fastening processes: Physics of welding, brazing and soldering;design considerationsin welding,Solid and liquid state joining processes;Adhesive bonding. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_MANUFACTURING_PROCESS">Grinding and Super finishing: Grinding: Grinding wheels, abrasive and bonds, cutting action. Grinding wheel specification. Grinding wheel wear - attritions wear, fracture wear. Dressing and Truing. Max chip thickness and Guest criteria. Surface and cylindrical grinding. Centreless grinding.  Super finishing: Honing, lapping and polishing. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_MANUFACTURING_PROCESS">Metal Joining (Welding): Survey of welding and allied processes. Gas welding and cutting, process and equipment. Arc welding: Power sources and consumables. TIG and MIG processes and their parameters. Resistance welding spot, seam projection etc. Other welding processes such as atomic hydrogen, submerged arc, electroslag, friction welding. Soldering and Brazing. Adhesive bonding. Weld decay in HAZ. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_MANUFACTURING_PROCESS">Unconventional Machining Processes: Abrasive Jet Machining, Water Jet Machining, Abrasive Water Jet Machining, UltrasonicMachining, principles and process parameters. Electrical Discharge Machining, principle and processes parameters, MRR, surface finish,tool wear, dielectric, power and control circuits, wire EDM; Electrochemical machining(ECM), etchant and maskant, process parameters, MRR and surface finish.Laser Beam Machining (LBM), Plasma Arc Machining (PAM) and Electron BeamMachining.
 </string>


    ME2YEAR SYLLABUS ENGINEERING_MECHANICS
    <string name="UNIT1_ME2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS">Two-dimensional force systems: Basic concepts, Laws of motion, Principle of transmissibility of forces, transfer of a force to parallel position, resultant of a force system, simplest resultant of two dimensional concurrent and non-concurrent force systems, distribution of force systems, free body diagrams, equilibrium and equations of equilibrium. Friction: Friction force – Laws of sliding friction – equilibrium analysis of simple systems with sliding friction – wedge friction. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ME2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS">Beam: Introduction, shear force and bending moment, different equations of equilibrium, shear force and bending moment diagram for statically determined beams. Trusses: Introduction, simple truss and solution of simple truss, methods of F-joint and methods of sections.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ME2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS">Centroid and moment of inertia: Centroid of plane, curve, area, volume and composite bodies, moment of inertia of plane area, parallel axis theorem, perpendicular axis theorem, principle moment of inertia, mass moment of inertia of circular ring, disc, cylinder, sphere, and cone about their axis of symmetry. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ME2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS">Kinematics of rigid body: Introduction, plane motion of rigid body, velocity and acceleration under translational and rotational motion, relative velocity. Kinetics of rigid body: Introduction, force, mass and acceleration, work and energy, impulse and momentum, D’Alembert’s principle and dynamic equilibrium. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ME2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS">Simple stress and strain: Introduction, normal and shear stresses, stress-strain diagrams for ductile and brittle material, elastic constants, one-dimensional loading of members of varying cross sections, strain energy. Pure bending of beams: Introduction, simple bending theory, stress in beams of different cross sections. Torsion: Introduction, torsion of shafts of circular cross sections, torque and twist, shear stress due to torque.
 </string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS MATERIALS_TESTING
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_MATERIALS_TESTING"> Scope of Study of building Materials: building materials and their performance, economics of the building materials. Stones: Requirement of good building stone, characteristics of building stone sand their testing. Common building stones.  Bricks: Manufacturing process of clay bricks, classification of clay bricks. Properties of clay bricks, testing methods for clay bricks. Problems of efflorescence and lime bursting in bricks and tiles. Different types of bricks. Gypsum: properties of gypsum plaster, building products made of gypsum and their uses. Cement: Raw materials used, Process of Manufacturing, Chemical composition, compounds formed and their effect on strength, Types of cement, Testing of cement properties, Uses of cement. Cement Concrete: Constituent materials and their properties, Grades of concrete, Factors affecting strength, Properties of concrete at fresh and hardened stage, Testing of concrete, Methods of Curing of concrete. Pozzolona: Chemical composition and requirements for uses, Natural and Artificial flyash, Surkhi(burnt clay pozzolona), rice husk and ash pozzolona, properties and specifications for use in construction. Timber: Classification and identification of timber, Fundamental Engineering Properties of timber, Defects in timber, Factor affecting strength of timber, Methods of seasoning and preservation of timber. Wood based products. Asphalt: Bitumen and Tar: Terminology, specifications and uses, Bituminous materials. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_MATERIALS_TESTING"> Plastics: classification, advantages of plastics, Mechanical properties and use of plastic in construction. Paints, varnishes and distempers: Common constituents, types and desirable properties, Cement paints. Ferrous metals: Desirable characteristics of reinforcing steel. Principles of cold working. Strength ,Telemechanical,  physical Properties and chemical composition. Brief discussion on properties and uses of Aluminum and lead. Glass: Ingredients, properties types and use in construction. Insulating Materials: Thermal and sound insulating material, desirable properties and types.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_MATERIALS_TESTING">Building Construction: Components of building area considerations, Construction Principle and Methods for layout, Damp proofing, anti termite treatment in buildings, Vertical circulation: stair cases and their types and planning. Different types of floors, and flooring materials .Bricks and stone masonry construction. Cavity wall and hollow block construction.  </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_MATERIALS_TESTING"> Doors and Windows: Construction details, types of doors and windows and their relative advantages and disadvantages. Types of roof and roof treatments, Lintel sand Chhajja, Principles of building Planning. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_MATERIALS_TESTING"> Natural Ventilation, Water Supply and Sanitary fittings (Plumbing), Electric Fittings. Heating Ventilation and Air conditioning (HVAC), Mechanical Lifts and Escalators, Fire Fighting and Fire Protection of Buildings. Acoustics. Plastering and its types, pointing, Distempering, Colour washing, Painting etc. Principles and Methods of building maintenance.</string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS FLUID_MECHANICS
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_FLUID_MECHANICS"> Fluid and continuum, Physical properties of fluids, Rheology of fluids. Pressure-density height relationship, manometers, pressure on plane and curved surfaces, centre of pressure, buoyancy, stability of immersed and floating bodies, fluid masses subjected to linear acceleration and uniform rotation about an axis</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_FLUID_MECHANICS"> Types of fluid flows: Continuum and free molecular flows. Steady and unsteady, uniform and non-uniform, laminar and turbulent flows, rotational and irrotational flows, compressible and incompressible flows, subsonic, sonic and supersonic flows, sub-critical, critical and supercritical flows, one, two and three dimensional flows, streamlines, path lines, streak lines, stream tube,  continuity equation for 1-D, 2-D and 3-D flows, circulation, stream function and velocity potential function.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_FLUID_MECHANICS"> Potential Flow: source, sink, doublet and half-body. Equation of motion along a streamline and its integration, Bernoulli’s equation and its applications- Pitot tube, orifice meter, venturimeter and bend meter, notches and weirs, momentum equation and its application to pipe bends. resistance to flow, Minor losses in pipe in series and parallel, power transmission through a pipe, siphon, water hammer, three reservoir problems and pipe networks.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_FLUID_MECHANICS"> Equation of motion for laminar flow through pipes, Stokes’ law, mixing length concept and velocity distribution in turbulent flow over smooth and rough surfaces, Boundary layer thickness, boundary layer over a flat plate, displacement, momentum and energy thickness. Application of momentum equation.  Laminar boundary layer,  turbulent boundary layer, laminar sub-layer, separation and its control. Vortex Flow: Free and Forced. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_FLUID_MECHANICS"> Drag and lift, drag on a sphere, aerofoil, Magnus effect, Similarity Laws; geometric, kinematics and dynamic similarity, undistorted and distorted model studies, Dimensional analysis, Buckingham’s Pi theorem, important dimensionless numbers and their significance. Introduction to Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD). </string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS SURVEYING_GEOMATICS
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_SURVEYING_GEOMATICS">Introduction to Surveying: Definition, Classification, Principles, Survey stations and Survey lines; Introduction to measurement of distance, direction and elevation; Ranging and it methods, Meridians and Bearings, Methods of leveling,  Booking and reducing levels, Reciprocal leveling, distance of visible horizon, Profile leveling and cross sectioning, Errors in leveling; Introduction to methods of plane table surveying; Contouring: Characteristics, methods, uses, computation of areas and volumes. Theodolite survey: Instruments, Measurement of horizontal and vertical angle; Methods of horizontal and vertical control, Triangulation: Figures or systems, Signals, Satellite station, Baseline and its importance, corrections, Trigonometric leveling: Accessible and inaccessible objects. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_SURVEYING_GEOMATICS">Curves: Elements of simple circular curves, Theory and methods of setting out simple circular curves, Transition curves- types, characteristics and equations of various transition curves; Introduction to vertical curves.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_SURVEYING_GEOMATICS">Modern Field Survey Systems: Principle and types of Electronic Distance Measurement systems and instruments, Total Station- its advantages and applications; Global Positioning Systems- Segments, working principle, errors and biases. Geographic Information System: Concepts and data types, data models, data acquisition. GIS applications in civil engineering. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_SURVEYING_GEOMATICS">Photogrammetric Survey: basic principles, aerial camera, scale of a vertical photograph, relief displacement of a vertical photograph, height of object from relief displacement, flight planning for aerial photography, selection of altitude, interval between exposures, crab and drift, stereoscope and stereoscopic views, parallax equations. Introduction to digital photogrammetry. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_SURVEYING_GEOMATICS">Remote Sensing: Concepts and physical basis of Remote Sensing, Electromagnetic spectrum, atmospheric effects, image characteristics. Remote sensing systems, spectral signatures and characteristics spectral reflectance curves. Salient features of some of Remote Sensing satellites missions. Digital image processing: Introduction, image rectification and restoration, image enhancement, image transformation, image classification. Applications of remote sensing to civil engineering</string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS HYDRAULIC
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_HYDRAULIC"> Introduction : Basic concepts of free surface flows, velocity and pressure distribution, Mass, energy and momentum principle for prismatic and non-prismatic channels critical, subcritical and super-critical type of flows. Critical depth, concepts of specific energy and specific force. Chezy’s and Manning’s equations for uniform flow in open channel, Velocity distribution, most efficient channel section, compound sections.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_HYDRAULIC"> Energy-Depth relationship: Application of specific energy principle for interpretation of open channel phenomena, flow through vertical and horizontal contractions. Equation of gradually varied flow and its limitations, flow classification and surface profiles, integration of varied flow equation by analytical, graphical and numerical methods. Measurments of discharge and velocity – Venturi flume, Standing wave flume, Parshall flume, Broad crested weir, Current meter and Floats. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_HYDRAULIC"> Rapidly varied flow: Hydraulic jump; Evaluation of the jump elements in rectangular channels on horizontal and sloping beds, energy dissipater, open channel surge, celerity of the gravity wave, deep and shallow water waves</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_HYDRAULIC"> Impulse momentum equation- Impact of Jets-plane and curved- stationary and moving plates. Pumps: Positive displacement pumps - reciprocating pumps , centrifugal pumps, operation, velocity triangles, performance curves, Cavitation, Multi staging, Selection of pumps</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_HYDRAULIC"> Rotodynamic Machines, Pelton Turbine, equations for jet and rotor size, efficiency, spear valve, reaction turbines, Francis and Kaplan type, Head on reaction turbine, unit quantities, similarity laws and specific speed, cavitation, characteristic curves.</string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS MATH3
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_MATH3">Laplace transform, Existence theorem, Laplace transforms of derivatives and integrals, Initial and final value theorems, Unit step function, Dirac- delta function, Laplace transform of periodic function, Inverse Laplace transform, Convolution theorem, Application to solve simple linear and simultaneous differential equations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_MATH3">Integral Transforms
Fourier integral, Fourier Transform , Complex Fourier transform, Inverse Transforms, Convolution Theorems, Fourier sine and cosine transform, Applications of Fourier transform to simple one dimensional heat transfer equations, wave equations and Laplace equations,  Z- Transform and its application to solve difference equations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_MATH3">Formal Logic ,Group, Ring and Field:  Introduction to First order logic, Proposition, Algebra of Proposition, Logical connectives, Tautologies, contradictions and contingency, Logical implication, Argument, Normal form, Rules of inferences, semi group, Monoid Group, Group, Cosets, Lagrange’s theorem , Congruence relation ,  Cyclic and permutation groups, Properties of groups,  Rings and Fields (definition, examples and standard results only) </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_MATH3">Set, Relation, function and Counting Techniques - Introduction of Sets, Relation and Function, Methods of Proof, Mathematical Induction, Strong Mathematical Induction, Discrete numeric function and Generating functions, recurrence relations and their solution , Pigeonhole principle. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_MATH3">Lattices and Boolean Algebra: Introduction, Partially ordered sets, Hasse Diagram, Maximal and Minimal element, Upper and Lower bounds, Isomorphic ordered sets, Lattices, Bounded Lattices and , Distributive Lattices.
Duality, Boolean Algebras as Lattices, Minimization of Boolean Expressions, prime Implicants, Logic Gates and Circuits, Truth Table, Boolean Functions, Karnaugh Maps. </string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS ENGINEERING_MECHANICS
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS"> Introduction to Engineering Mechanics: Force Systems, Basic concepts, Rigid Body equilibrium; System of Forces, Coplanar Concurrent Forces, Components in Space – Resultant- Moment of Forces and its Applications; Couples and Resultant of Force System, Equilibrium of System of Forces, Free body diagrams, Equations of Equilibrium of Coplanar Systems. Friction: Types of friction, Limiting friction, Laws of Friction, Static and Dynamic Friction; Motion of Bodies, wedge friction, screw jack and differential screw jack;</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS"> Centroid and Centre of Gravity, Centroid of simple figures from first principle, centroid of composite sections; Centre of Gravity and its implications; Area moment of inertia- Definition, Moment of inertia of plane sections from first principles, Theorems of moment of inertia, Moment of inertia of standard sections and composite sections; Mass moment inertia of circular plate, Cylinder, Cone, Sphere, Hook.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS"> Basic Structural Analysis, Equilibrium in three dimensions; Analysis of simple trusses by method of sections and method of joints, Zero force members, Simple beams and support reactions. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS"> Review of particle dynamics- Rectilinear motion; Plane curvilinear motion (rectangular, path, and polar coordinates). Work-kinetic energy, power, potential energy. Impulse-momentum (linear, angular); Impact (Direct and oblique).</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_ENGINEERING_MECHANICS">V Introduction to Kinetics of Rigid Bodies, Basic terms, general principles in dynamics; Types of motion, Instantaneous centre of rotation in plane motion and simple problems; D’Alembert’s principle and its applications in plane motion and connected bodies; Work energy principle and its application in plane motion of connected bodies; Kinetics of rigid body rotation Virtual Work and Energy Method- Virtual displacements, principle of virtual work for particle and ideal system of rigid bodies, Applications of energy method for equilibrium, Stability of equilibrium.</string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS SCIENCE_COURCE
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS HUMAN_VALUES
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_HUMAN_VALUES">Course Introduction - Need, Basic Guidelines, Content and Process for Value Education
 Understanding the need, basic guidelines, content and process for Value Education, Self-Exploration–what is it? - its content and process; ‘Natural Acceptance’ and  Experiential Validation- as the mechanism for self exploration, Continuous Happiness and Prosperity- A look at basic Human Aspirations, Right understanding, Relationship and Physical Facilities- the basic requirements for fulfillment of aspirations of every human being with their correct priority, Understanding Happiness and Prosperity correctly- A critical appraisal of the current scenario, Method to fulfill  the above human aspirations: understanding and living in harmony at various levels.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Human Being - Harmony in Myself
 Understanding human being as a co-existence of the sentient ‘I’ and the material ‘Body’, Understanding the needs of Self (‘I’) and ‘Body’ - Sukh and Suvidha, Understanding the Body as an instrument of ‘I’ (I being the doer, seer and enjoyer), Understanding the characteristics and activities of ‘I’ and harmony in ‘I’, Understanding the harmony of I with the Body: Sanyam and Swasthya; correct appraisal of Physical needs, meaning of Prosperity in detail,  Programs to  ensure Sanyam and Swasthya. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Family and Society- Harmony in Human-Human Relationship
 Understanding harmony in the Family- the basic unit of human interaction , Understanding values in human-human relationship; meaning of Nyaya and program for its fulfillment to ensure Ubhay-tripti; Trust (Vishwas) and Respect (Samman) as the foundational values of relationship, Understanding the meaning of Vishwas; Difference between intention and competence, Understanding the meaning of Samman, Difference between respect and differentiation; the other salient values in relationship, Understanding the harmony in the society (society being an extension of family): Samadhan, Samridhi, Abhay, Sah-astitva as comprehensive Human Goals, Visualizing a universal harmonious order in society- Undivided Society (AkhandSamaj), Universal Order (SarvabhaumVyawastha )- from family to world family!.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Nature and Existence - Whole existence as Co-existence
 Understanding the harmony in the Nature, Interconnectedness and mutual fulfillment among the four orders of nature- recyclability and self-regulation in nature,  Understanding Existence as Co-existence (Sah-astitva) of mutually interacting units in all-pervasive space, Holistic perception of harmony at all levels of existence.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_HUMAN_VALUES">Implications of the above Holistic Understanding of Harmony on Professional Ethics
 Natural acceptance of human values, Definitiveness of Ethical  Human Conduct, Basis for Humanistic Education, Humanistic Constitution and Humanistic Universal Order, Competence in Professional Ethics: a) Ability to utilize the professional competence for augmenting universal human order,  b) Ability to identify the scope and characteristics of people-friendly and eco-friendly </string>


    CIVIL2YEAR SYLLABUS SOLID_MECHANICS
    <string name="UNIT1_CIVIL2_SOLID_MECHANICS"> Simple stress and strains:  Concept of stress and strain, types of stresses and strains, Hook’s law, stress and strain diagram for ductile and brittle metal. Lateral strain, Poission ratio, volumetric strain, elastic moduli and relation between them. Bar of varying cross section, composite bar and temperature stress. Strain energy for gradual, sudden and impact loading.  Compound stress and strains: Normal stress and strain, shear stress and strain, stresses on inclines sections, principal stress and strain, maximum shear stress, Mohr’s stress circle, three dimensional state of stress and strain, equilibrium equations, generalized Hook’s law-3D, Theories of failure and factor of safety</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_CIVIL2_SOLID_MECHANICS"> Shear force and bending moment diagrams Shear force (SF) and Bending moment (BM) diagrams for simply supported, cantilevers, overhanging and fixed beams. Calculation of maximum BM and SF and the point of contra flexure under concentrated loads, uniformly distributed loads over the whole span or part of span, combination of concentrated loads (two or three) and uniformly distributed loads, uniformly varying loads. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_CIVIL2_SOLID_MECHANICS"> Flexural Stresses-Theory of simple bending – Assumptions – Derivation of bending equation: M/I = f/y = E/R - Neutral axis – Determination of bending stresses – Section modulus of rectangular and circular sections (Solid and Hollow), I,T, Angle and Channel sections – Design of simple beam sections. Torsion- Derivation of torsion equation and its assumptions. Applications of the equation of the hollow and solid circular shafts, torsional rigidity, Combined torsion and bending of circular shafts, principal stress and maximum shear stresses under combined loading of bending and torsion.  Shear Stresses- Derivation of formula – Shear stress distribution across various beam sections like rectangular, circular, triangular, I, T angle sections.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_CIVIL2_SOLID_MECHANICS"> Deflection of Beams:  Slope and deflection- Relationship between moment, slope and deflection, Moment area method, Macaulay’s method. Use of these methods to calculate slope and deflection for determinant beams. Short Columns and Struts: Buckling and stability, slenderness ratio, combined bending and direct stress, middle third and middle quarter rules.</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_CIVIL2_SOLID_MECHANICS"> Helical and Leaf Springs: Deflection of springs by energy method, helical springs under axial load and under axial twist (respectively for circular and square cross sections) axial load and twisting moment acting simultaneously both for open and closed coiled springs.  Thin cylinders, Thick cylinders and Spheres: Introduction, difference between thin walled and thick walled pressure vessels, thin walled spheres and cylinders, hoop and axial stresses and strain, volumetric strain. Radial, axial and circumferential stresses in thick cylinders subjected to internal or external pressures, compound cylinders. </string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS SCIENCE_COURCE
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_SCIENCE_COURCE"></string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS NETWORK_ANALYSIS
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_NETWORK_ANALYSIS">Graph Theory:  Pre- Requisites: Basic circuital law, Mesh and Nodal analysis. Importance of Graph Theory in Network Analysis, Graph of a network, Definitions, planar and NonPlanar Graphs, Isomorphism, Tree, Co Tree, Link, basic loop and basic cutset, Incidence matrix, Cut set matrix, Tie set matrix, Duality, Loop and Nodal methods of analysis. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_NETWORK_ANALYSIS">AC Network Theorems (Applications to dependent and independent sources):  Pre- Requisites: Concepts of DC Network Theorems, Electrical Sources and Basic circuital law. Superposition theorem, Thevenin’s theorem, Norton’s theorem, Maximum power transfer theorem, Reciprocity theorem. Millman’s theorem, Compensation theorem, Tellegen’s Theorem. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_NETWORK_ANALYSIS">Transient Circuit Analysis: Pre- Requisites: Laplace Transform and Concept of Initial conditions. Natural response and forced response, Transient response andsteady state response for arbitrary inputs (DC and AC), Evaluation of time response both through classical and Laplace methods. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_NETWORK_ANALYSIS">Network Functions: Pre- Requisites: Concept of basic circuital law, parallel, series circuits. Concept of complex frequency, Transform impedances network functions of one port and two port networks, Concept of poles and zeros, Properties of driving point and transfer functions. Two Port Networks- Characterization of LTI two port networks; Z, Y,ABCD, A’B’C’D’, g and h parameters, Reciprocity and symmetry, Inter-relationships between the parameters, Inter-connections of two port networks, Ladder and Lattice networks: T and Π representation, terminated two Port networks, Image Impedance.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_NETWORK_ANALYSIS">(a)Network Synthesis: Pre- Requisites: Laplace Transform, Concept of immittance functions.  Positive real function; definition and properties, Properties of LC, RC and RL driving point functions, Synthesis of LC, RC and RL driving point immittance functions using Foster and Cauer first and second forms. </string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS ELECTRICAL_MEASUREMENTS
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MEASUREMENTS">Electrical Measurements: Measurement system, Characteristics of instruments, Methods of measurement, Errors in Measurement and  Measurement standards, Review of indicating and integrating instruments: Voltmeter, Ammeter and Wattmeter. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MEASUREMENTS">Measurement of Resistance, Inductance and Capacitance: Measurement of low, medium and high resistances, insulation resistance measurement, AC bridges for inductance and capacitance measurement. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MEASUREMENTS">Instrument Transformers: Current and Potential transformer, ratio and phase angle errors, design considerations and testing.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MEASUREMENTS">Electronic Measurements: Electronic instruments: Voltmeter, Multimeter, Wattmeter and energy meter. Time, Frequency and phase angle measurements using CRO; Storage oscilloscope, Spectrum and Wave analyzer,Digital counter, frequency meter,and Digital Voltmeter. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MEASUREMENTS">Instrumentation:Transducers and sensors,classification and selection of sensors, Measurement of force using strain gauges, Measurement of pressure using piezoelectric sensor, Measurement of temperature using Thermistors and Thermocouples, Measurement of displacement using LVDT, Measurement of position using Hall effect sensors.Concept of signal conditioning and data acquisition systems, Concept of smart sensors and virtual instrumentation. </string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS ELECTROMAGNETIC
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_ELECTROMAGNETIC">Coordinate Systems and Transformation: Basics of Vectors: Addition, subtraction and multiplications; Cartesian, Cylindrical, Spherical transformation. Vector calculus: Differential length, area and volume, line surface and volume integrals, Del operator, Gradient, Divergence of a vector, Divergence theorem, Curl of a vector, Stokes’s theorem, Laplacian of a scalar. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_ELECTROMAGNETIC">Electrostatic fields: Coulombs law and field intensity, Electric field due to charge distribution, Electric flux density, Gausses’ Law- Maxwell’s equation, Electric dipole and flux line, Energy density in electrostatic fields, Electric field in material space: Properties of materials, convection and conduction currents, conductors, polarization in dielectrics, Dielectric-constants, Continuity equation and relaxation time, boundary conditions, Electrostatic boundary value problems: Poisson’s and Laplace’s equations., Methods of Images. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_ELECTROMAGNETIC">Magneto statics : Magneto-static fields, Biot - Savart’s Law, Ampere’s circuit law, Maxwell’s equation, Application of ampere’s law, Magnetic flux density- Maxwell’s equation, Maxwell’s equation for static fields, magnetic scalar and vector potential. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_ELECTROMAGNETIC">Magnetic forces: Materials and devices, Forces due to magnetic field, Magnetic torque and moment, a magnetic dipole. Magnetization in materials, Magnetic boundary conditions, Inductors and inductances, Magnetic energy. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_ELECTROMAGNETIC">Waves and Applications: Maxwell’s equation, Faraday’s Law, transformer and motional electromotive forces, Displacement current, Maxwell’s equation in final form Electromagnetic wave propagation: Wave propagation in loss dielectrics, Plane waves in lossless dielectrics Plane wave in free space. Plain waves in good conductors, Power and the pointing vector, Reflection of a plain wave in a normal incidence. Transmission Lines and Smith Chart. </string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS DIGITAL_ELECTRONICS
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_DIGITAL_ELECTRONICS">Digital System And Binary Numbers: Number System and its arithmetic, Signed binary numbers, Binary codes, Cyclic codes, Hamming Code, the map method up to five variable, Don’t care conditions, POS simplification, NAND and NOR implementation, Quine McClusky method (Tabular method)</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_DIGITAL_ELECTRONICS">Combinational Logic: Combinational Circuits: Analysis Procedure, Design procedure, Binary addersubtractor, Decimal adder, Binary multiplier, Magnitude comparator, Multiplexers, Demultiplexers, Decoders, Encoders.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_DIGITAL_ELECTRONICS"> Sequential Logic And Its Applications: Storage elements: latches and flip flops, Characteristic Equations of Flip Flops, Flip Flop Conversion, Shift Registers, Ripple Counters, Synchronous Counters, Other Counters: Johnson and Ring Counter. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_DIGITAL_ELECTRONICS">Synchronous and Asynchronous Sequential Circuits: Analysis of clocked sequential circuits with state machine designing, State reduction and assignments, Design procedure. Analysis procedure of Asynchronous sequential circuits, circuit with latches, Design procedure, Reduction of state and flow table, Race-free state assignment, Hazards. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_DIGITAL_ELECTRONICS">Memory and Programmable Logic Devices: Digital Logic Families: DTL, DCTL, TTL, ECL and CMOS etc., Fan Out, Fan in, Noise Margin; RAM, ROM, PLA, PAL; Circuits of Logic Families, Interfacing of Digital Logic Families, Circuit Implementation using ROM, PLA and PAL; CPLD and FPGA. </string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS HUMAN_VALUES
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_HUMAN_VALUES">Course Introduction - Need, Basic Guidelines, Content and Process for Value Education
 Understanding the need, basic guidelines, content and process for Value Education, Self-Exploration–what is it? - its content and process; ‘Natural Acceptance’ and  Experiential Validation- as the mechanism for self exploration, Continuous Happiness and Prosperity- A look at basic Human Aspirations, Right understanding, Relationship and Physical Facilities- the basic requirements for fulfillment of aspirations of every human being with their correct priority, Understanding Happiness and Prosperity correctly- A critical appraisal of the current scenario, Method to fulfill  the above human aspirations: understanding and living in harmony at various levels.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Human Being - Harmony in Myself
 Understanding human being as a co-existence of the sentient ‘I’ and the material ‘Body’, Understanding the needs of Self (‘I’) and ‘Body’ - Sukh and Suvidha, Understanding the Body as an instrument of ‘I’ (I being the doer, seer and enjoyer), Understanding the characteristics and activities of ‘I’ and harmony in ‘I’, Understanding the harmony of I with the Body: Sanyam and Swasthya; correct appraisal of Physical needs, meaning of Prosperity in detail,  Programs to  ensure Sanyam and Swasthya. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Family and Society- Harmony in Human-Human Relationship
 Understanding harmony in the Family- the basic unit of human interaction , Understanding values in human-human relationship; meaning of Nyaya and program for its fulfillment to ensure Ubhay-tripti; Trust (Vishwas) and Respect (Samman) as the foundational values of relationship, Understanding the meaning of Vishwas; Difference between intention and competence, Understanding the meaning of Samman, Difference between respect and differentiation; the other salient values in relationship, Understanding the harmony in the society (society being an extension of family): Samadhan, Samridhi, Abhay, Sah-astitva as comprehensive Human Goals, Visualizing a universal harmonious order in society- Undivided Society (AkhandSamaj), Universal Order (SarvabhaumVyawastha )- from family to world family!.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_HUMAN_VALUES">Understanding Harmony in the Nature and Existence - Whole existence as Co-existence
 Understanding the harmony in the Nature, Interconnectedness and mutual fulfillment among the four orders of nature- recyclability and self-regulation in nature,  Understanding Existence as Co-existence (Sah-astitva) of mutually interacting units in all-pervasive space, Holistic perception of harmony at all levels of existence.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_HUMAN_VALUES">Implications of the above Holistic Understanding of Harmony on Professional Ethics
 Natural acceptance of human values, Definitiveness of Ethical  Human Conduct, Basis for Humanistic Education, Humanistic Constitution and Humanistic Universal Order, Competence in Professional Ethics: a) Ability to utilize the professional competence for augmenting universal human order,  b) Ability to identify the scope and characteristics of people-friendly and eco-friendly </string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS MATH3
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_MATH3">Laplace transform, Existence theorem, Laplace transforms of derivatives and integrals, Initial and final value theorems, Unit step function, Dirac- delta function, Laplace transform of periodic function, Inverse Laplace transform, Convolution theorem, Application to solve simple linear and simultaneous differential equations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_MATH3">Integral Transforms
Fourier integral, Fourier Transform , Complex Fourier transform, Inverse Transforms, Convolution Theorems, Fourier sine and cosine transform, Applications of Fourier transform to simple one dimensional heat transfer equations, wave equations and Laplace equations,  Z- Transform and its application to solve difference equations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_MATH3">Formal Logic ,Group, Ring and Field:  Introduction to First order logic, Proposition, Algebra of Proposition, Logical connectives, Tautologies, contradictions and contingency, Logical implication, Argument, Normal form, Rules of inferences, semi group, Monoid Group, Group, Cosets, Lagrange’s theorem , Congruence relation ,  Cyclic and permutation groups, Properties of groups,  Rings and Fields (definition, examples and standard results only) </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_MATH3">Set, Relation, function and Counting Techniques - Introduction of Sets, Relation and Function, Methods of Proof, Mathematical Induction, Strong Mathematical Induction, Discrete numeric function and Generating functions, recurrence relations and their solution , Pigeonhole principle. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_MATH3">Lattices and Boolean Algebra: Introduction, Partially ordered sets, Hasse Diagram, Maximal and Minimal element, Upper and Lower bounds, Isomorphic ordered sets, Lattices, Bounded Lattices and , Distributive Lattices.
Duality, Boolean Algebras as Lattices, Minimization of Boolean Expressions, prime Implicants, Logic Gates and Circuits, Truth Table, Boolean Functions, Karnaugh Maps. </string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS_1
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS_1">Principles of Electro-mechanical Energy Conversion: Introduction, Review of magnetic system, Energy in Magnetic system, Force and torque in magnetic field system, Energy balance equation, Energy conversion via electrical field, Energy in a singly excited system, Determination of the Force and Torque from energy and co-energy, Generation of EMF in Machines, Torque in machine with cylindrical air gap. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS_1">Pre- Requisites: Principle and Construction, Classification and circuit model, EMF equation of generator and torque equation of motor
DC Machines: Armature winding (Concentrated and Distributed), Winding Factor, Armature reaction, Commutation, Interpoles and compensating windings, Performance characteristics of DC generators, Applications.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS_1">DC Machines: Performance characteristics of DC motors, Starting of DC motors; 3 point and 4 point starters, Speed control of DC motors; Field control, Armature control and Voltage control (Ward Leonard method); Efficiency and Testing of DC machines (Hopkinson and Swinburne Test), Applications, Introduction to Brushless DC Motor, stepper motor and DC Servo motor and their applications. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS_1">Single Phase Transformer: Efficiency and voltage regulation, all day efficiency, Excitation phenomenon and harmonics in transformers. Testing of Transformers- O.C. and S.C. tests, Polarity test, Sumpner test.  Auto Transformer- Single phase and three phase autotransformers, Volt-amp relation, Copper saving in autotransformer Efficiency, Merits and demerits and applications.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_ELECTRICAL_MECHANICS_1">Three Phase Transformers: Construction, Three phase transformer, phasor groups and their connections, open delta connection, three phase to 2 phase and their applications, Three winding transformers. Parallel operation of single phase and three phase transformers and load sharing. </string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS BASIC_SIGNALS
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_BASIC_SIGNALS">Introduction to Continuous Time Signals and Systems: Introduction to continuous time and discrete time signals, Classification of signals with their mathematical representation and characteristics. Transformation of independent variable, Introduction to various type of system, basic system properties. Analogous System: Linear and Rotational mechanical elements, force-voltage and force-current analogy, modeling of mechanical and electro-mechanical systems: Analysis of first and second order linear systems by classical method. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_BASIC_SIGNALS">Fourier Transform Analysis: Exponential form and Compact trigonometric form of Fourier series, Fourier symmetry, Fourier transform: Properties, application to network analysis. Definition of DTFS, and DTFT, Sampling Theorem. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_BASIC_SIGNALS">Laplace Transform Analysis: Review of Laplace Transform, Properties of Laplace Transform, Initial and Final value Theorems, Inverse Laplace Transform, Convolution Theorem, Impulse response, Application of Laplace Transform to analysis of networks, waveform synthesis and Laplace Transform to complex waveforms </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_BASIC_SIGNALS">State – Variable analysis: Introduction, State Space representation of linear systems, Transfer function and state Variables, State Transition Matrix, Solution of state equations for homogeneous and non-homogeneous systems, Applications of State – Variable technique to the analysis of linear systems. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_BASIC_SIGNALS">Z – Transform Analysis: Concept of Z – Transform and ROC, Z – Transform of common functions, Inverse Z – Transform, Initial and Final value Theorems, Applications to solution of difference equations, Properties of Z-transform. </string>


    EE2YEAR SYLLABUS TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION
    <string name="UNIT1_EE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_EE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_EE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_EE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_EE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS NETWORKS_ANALYSIS
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_NETWORKS_ANALYSIS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_NETWORKS_ANALYSIS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_NETWORKS_ANALYSIS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_NETWORKS_ANALYSIS"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_NETWORKS_ANALYSIS"></string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS ELECTRONICS_DEVICES
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_ELECTRONICS_DEVICES"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_ELECTRONICS_DEVICES"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_ELECTRONICS_DEVICES"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_ELECTRONICS_DEVICES"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_ELECTRONICS_DEVICES"></string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS HUMAN_VALUES
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_HUMAN_VALUES"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_HUMAN_VALUES"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_HUMAN_VALUES"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_HUMAN_VALUES"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_HUMAN_VALUES"></string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS MATH3
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_MATH3"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_MATH3"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_MATH3"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_MATH3"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_MATH3"></string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS SCIENCE_COURSE
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_SCIENCE_COURSE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_SCIENCE_COURSE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_SCIENCE_COURSE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_SCIENCE_COURSE"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_SCIENCE_COURSE"></string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS SIGNAL_SYSTEM
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_SIGNAL_SYSTEM">Signals and systems as seen in everyday life, and in various branches of engineering and science, energy and power signals, continuous and discrete time signals, continuous and discrete amplitude signals, system properties: linearity, additivity and homogeneity, shift-invariance, causality, stability, realizability. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_SIGNAL_SYSTEM">Linear shift-invariant (LSI) systems, impulse response and step response, convolution, input-output behaviour with aperiodic convergent inputs, characterization of causality and stability of linear shift invariant systems, system representation through differential equations and difference equations, Periodic and semi-periodic inputs to an LSI system, the notion of a frequency response and its relation to the impulse response </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_SIGNAL_SYSTEM">Fourier series representation, Fourier transform, convolution/multiplication and their effect in the frequency domain, magnitude and phase response, Fourier domain duality , Discrete-Time Fourier Transform (DTFT) and the Discrete Fourier transform (DFT), Parseval\'s Theorem, the idea of signal space and orthogonal bases, the Laplace transform, notion of Eigen functions of LSI systems, a basis of Eigen functions, region of convergence, poles and zeros of system, Laplace domain analysis, solution to differential equations and system behaviour</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_SIGNAL_SYSTEM">The z-Transform for discrete time signals and systems-Eigen functions, region of convergence, z-domain analysis. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_SIGNAL_SYSTEM">The sampling theorem and its implications- spectra of sampled signals, reconstruction: ideal interpolator, zero-order hold, first-order hold, and so on, aliasing and its effects, relation between continuous and discrete time systems.
</string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_TECHNICAL_COMMUNICATION"></string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS ANALOG_CIRCUIT
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_ANALOG_CIRCUIT">Diode circuits, amplifier models: Voltage amplifier, current amplifier, trans-conductance amplifier and trans-resistance amplifier. biasing schemes for BJT and FET amplifiers, bias stability, various configurations (such as CE/CS, CB/CG, CC/CD) and their features, small signal analysis, low frequency transistor models, estimation of voltage gain, input resistance, output resistance etc., design procedure for particular specifications, low frequency analysis of multistage amplifiers.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_ANALOG_CIRCUIT">High frequency transistor models, frequency response of single stage and multistage amplifiers, cascode amplifier, various classes of operation (Class A, B, AB, C etc.), their power efficiency and linearity issues, feedback topologies: Voltage series, current series, voltage shunt, current shunt, effect of feedback on gain, bandwidth etc., calculation with practical circuits, concept of stability, gain margin and phase margin.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_ANALOG_CIRCUIT">Oscillators: Review of the basic concept, Barkhausen criterion, RC oscillators (phase shift, Wien bridge etc.), LC oscillators (Hartley, Colpitt, Clapp etc.), non-sinusoidal oscillators.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_ANALOG_CIRCUIT">Current mirror: Basic topology and its variants, V-I characteristics, output resistance and minimum sustainable voltage (VON), maximum usable load, differential amplifier: Basic structure and principle of operation, calculation of differential gain, common mode gain, CMRR and ICMR, Op-Amp design: Design of differential amplifier for a given specification, design of gain stages and output stages, compensation.</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_ANALOG_CIRCUIT">Op-Amp applications: Review of inverting and non-inverting amplifiers, integrator and differentiator, summing amplifier, precision rectifier, Schmitt trigger and its applications, active filters: Low pass, high pass, band pass and band stop, design guidelines.</string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS COMMUNICATION_ENGINEERING
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_COMMUNICATION_ENGINEERING">Review of signals and systems, frequency domain representation of signals, principles of amplitude modulation systems- DSB, SSB and VSB modulations. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_COMMUNICATION_ENGINEERING"> Angle modulation, representation of FM and PM signals, spectral characteristics of angle modulated signals. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_COMMUNICATION_ENGINEERING"> Review of probability and random process, Gaussian and white noise characteristics, noise in amplitude modulation systems, noise in frequency modulation systems, pre-emphasis and de-emphasis, threshold effect in angle modulation.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_COMMUNICATION_ENGINEERING">Pulse modulation, sampling process, pulse amplitude and pulse code modulation (PCM), differential pulse code modulation. Delta modulation, noise considerations in PCM, time division multiplexing, digital multiplexers.  </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_COMMUNICATION_ENGINEERING"> Digital modulation schemes- phase shift keying, frequency shift keying, quadrature amplitude modulation, continuous phase modulation and minimum shift keying. </string>


    ECE2YEAR SYLLABUS DIGITAL_SYSTEM_DESIGN
    <string name="UNIT1_ECE2_DIGITAL_SYSTEM_DESIGN"></string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ECE2_DIGITAL_SYSTEM_DESIGN"></string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ECE2_DIGITAL_SYSTEM_DESIGN"></string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ECE2_DIGITAL_SYSTEM_DESIGN"></string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ECE2_DIGITAL_SYSTEM_DESIGN"></string>


    COMMON FIRST YEAR SYLLABUS


    COMMON FIRST YEAR SYLLABUS ENGINEERING_CHEMISTRY
    <string name="UNIT1_ENGINEERING_CHEMISTRY">Module-1  Atomic and Molecular Structure:
        Molecular orbital‟s of diatomic molecules. Band theory of solids. Liquid crystal and its applications. Point defects in solids. Structure and applications of Graphite and Fullerenes. Concepts of Nanomaterials and its application. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ENGINEERING_CHEMISTRY">Module-2   Spectroscopic techniques and Applications:
        Elementary idea and simple applications of Rotational, Vibrational, Ultraviolet and Visible and Raman spectroscopy. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ENGINEERING_CHEMISTRY">Module-3   Electrochemistry
        Nernst Equation and application, relation of EMF with thermodynamic functions (∆H, ∆F and ∆ S). Lead storage battery. Corrosion; causes, effects and its prevention.  Phase Rule and its application to water system. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ENGINEERING_CHEMISTRY">Module-4   Water Analysis;
        Hardness of water, Techniques for water softening (Lime-soda, Zeolite, Ion exchange resin and Reverse osmosis method). Fuels: classification of fuels, Analysis of coal, Determination of calorific value (Bomb calorimeterand Dulong‟smethos). </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ENGINEERING_CHEMISTRY">Module-5    Polymer;
        Basic concepts of polymer-Blend and composites, Conducting and biodegradable polymers. Preparation and application of some industrially important polymers (Buna-S, Buna-N, Neoprene, Nylon-6, nylon-6,6 and Terylene). General methods of synthesis of organometallic compounds (Grignard reagent) and their applications. </string>


    COMMON FIRST YEAR SYLLABUS ELECTRICAL
    <string name="UNIT1_ELECTRICAL">Module -  1: DC Circuits
Electrical circuit elements (R, L and C), Concept of active and passive elements, voltage and current sources, concept of linearity and linear network, unilateral and bilateral elements, Kirchhoff‟s laws, Loop and nodal methods of analysis, Star-delta transformation, Superposition theorem, Thevenin theorem, Norton theorem.</string>
    <string name="UNIT2_ELECTRICAL">Module - 2: Steady- State Analysis of Single Phase AC Circuits
Representation of Sinusoidal waveforms – Average and effective values, Form and peak factors, Concept of phasors, phasor representation of sinusoidally varying voltage and current.
Analysis of single phase AC Circuits consisting of R, L, C, RL, RC, RLC combinations (Series and Parallel), Apparent, active and reactive power, Power factor, power factor improvement. Concept of Resonance in series and parallel circuits, bandwidth and quality factor.
Three phase balanced circuits, voltage and current relations in star and delta connections. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_ELECTRICAL">Module - 3 : Transformers
Magnetic materials, BH characteristics, ideal and practical transformer, equivalent circuit, losses in transformers, regulation and efficiency. Auto-transformer and three-phase transformer connections. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_ELECTRICAL">Module –4 : Electrical machines
DC machines: Principle and Construction, Types, EMF equation of generator and torque equation of motor, applications of DC motors (simple numerical problems)
Three Phase Induction Motor: Principle and Construction, Types, Slip-torque characteristics, Applications (Numerical problems related to slip only)
Single Phase Induction motor: Principle of operation and introduction to methods of starting, applications.
Three Phase Synchronous Machines: Principle of operation of alternator and synchronous motor and their applications.</string>
    <string name="UNIT5_ELECTRICAL">Module –5 :  Electrical Installations
Components of LT Switchgear: Switch Fuse Unit (SFU), MCB, ELCB, MCCB, Types of Wires and Cables, Importance of earthing. Types of Batteries, Important characteristics for Batteries.Elementary calculations for energy consumption and savings, battery backup. </string>


    COMMON FIRST YEAR SYLLABUS PROFESSIONAL_ENGLISH
    <string name="UNIT1_PROFESSIONAL_ENGLISH">Module 1- Basics of Technical English
Technical English: Definition;  Extent and Coverage; Dimensions; Reading; Skimming; Scanning; Churning and Assimilation; Writing: Methods: Inductive; Deductive; Exposition; Linear; Interrupted; Spatial and Chronological etc;  Technical Communication; Approaches: Brevity; Objectivity; Simplicity; Utility and Clarity. Listening: Active; Passive; Thinking strategies: Positive and Logical thinking; Speaking: Essentials Nuances and Modes of Speech Delivery. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_PROFESSIONAL_ENGLISH">Module 2- Components of Technical Writing
Vocabulary Building: Select words; Concept of word formation; Word formation; Root words from foreign languages and their use in English; Prefixes and Suffixes: Derivatives; Synonyms; Antonyms; Abbreviations. Homophones. One word substitutes; Requisites of Sentences.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_PROFESSIONAL_ENGLISH">Module 3- Basic Technical Writing Skills
Forms: Business writing: Principle; Purchase and Sales Letters; Drafts; Official Writing: Official Letter; D.O. Letter; Notices; Agenda; Minutes of Meeting; Sentence Structure; Phrases and Clauses in sentences; Coherence; Unity; Emphasis in Writing; Devices; Use of Writing methods in Documents; Techniques of writing. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_PROFESSIONAL_ENGLISH">Module 4- Common Grammatical Errors and Technical Style
Subject-verb agreement; Correct usage: Noun; Pronoun; Agreement; Modifiers; Articles; Prepositions; Cliches; Redundancies; Technical Style: Features; Choice of words; Sentences: Descriptive; Narrative; Expository; Defining and Classifying; Length of paragraph; Writing of Introduction and Conclusion. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_PROFESSIONAL_ENGLISH">Module 5- Presentation Strategies and Oral Communications
        Analysis of locale; Audience; Modulating Style and Content; Speaking with confidence; Kinesics; Paralinguistic features of Voice-Dynamics: Pitch; Intonation; Stress and Rhythm; Conversation and dialogues; Communication at work-place; etc.</string>


    COMMON FIRST YEAR SYLLABUS GRAPHICS
    <string name="UNIT1_GRAPHICS">Module 1: Introduction to Engineering Drawing, Orthographic Projections
Principles of Engineering Graphics and their significance, usage of Drawing instruments, lettering, Scales – Plain and Diagonal Scales Principles of Orthographic Projections – Conventions – Projections of Points and Lines inclined to both planes; Projections of planes inclined Planes – Auxiliary Planes. </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_GRAPHICS">Module 2: Projections and Sections of Regular Solids
Sections in lined to both the Planes – Auxiliary Views; Simple annotation, dimensioning and scale. Floor plans the include: windows, doors and fixtures such as WC, Both, sink, shower, etc. Prism, Cylinder, Pyramid, Cone – Auxiliary Vies: Development of surfaces of Right Regular Solids – Prism, Pyramid, Cylinder and Cone.  </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_GRAPHICS">Module 3: Isometric Projections
Principles of Isometric projection – Isometric Scale, Isometric Views, Conventions; Isometric Views of lines, Planes Simple and compound Solids; Conversion of Isometric Views to Orthographic Views and Viceversa, Conversions.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_GRAPHICS">Module 4: Computer Graphics
Listing the computer technologies the impact on graphical communication, Demonstration knowledge of the theory of CAD software [such as: The Menu System, Tollbars (Standard, Object Properties, Draw, Modify and Dimension), Drawing Area (Background, Crosshairs, Coordinate System), Dialog boxes and windows, Shortcut menus (Button Bars), The  Command Line (where applicable), The Status Bar, Different methods of zoom as used in CAD, Select and erase objects: Isometric Views of lines, Planes, Simple and compound Solids];

Set up of the drawing page and the printer, including scale settings, Setting up of units and drawing limits; ISO and ANSI standards for coordinate dimensioning and tolerancing; Orthographic constraints, Snap to objects manually and automatically; Producing drawings by using various coordinate input entry methods to draw straight lines, Applying various ways of drawing circles:

Applying dimensions to objects, applying annotations to drawings; Setting up and use of Layers, layers to create drawings, Create, edit and use customized layers; Changing line lengths through modifying existing lines (extend/lengthen); Printing documents to pater using the print command: orthographic projection techniques; Drawing sectional views of composite right regular geometric solids and project the true shape of the sectioned surface; Drawing annotation, Computer-aided design (CAD) software modelling of parts and assemblies. Parametric and non-parametric solid, surface, and wireframe models. Part editing and twodimensional documentation of models. Planar projection theory, including sketching of perspective, isometric, Multi view, auxiliary, and section views. Spatial visualization exercises Dimensioning guidelines, tolerancing techniques; dimensioning and scale multi views of dwelling:
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_GRAPHICS">Module 5: Demonstration of a simple team design project
Geometry and topology of engineered components: creation of engineering models and their presentation in standard 2D blueprint form and as 3D wire-frame and shaded solids; meshed topologies for engineering analysis and tool-path generation for component manufacture; geometric dimensioning and tolerancing; Use of solid-modelling software for creating associative models at the component and assembly levels; floor plans that include: windows,  doors, and fixtures such as WC, bath, sink, shower, etc. Applying colour coding according to building drawing practice; Drawing sectional elevation showing foundation to ceiling; Introduction to Building Information Modelling (BIM).
 </string>


    COMMON FIRST YEAR SYLLABUS MATHS1
    <string name="UNIT1_MATHS1">Module 1: Matrices
Types of Matrices: Symmetric, Skew-symmetric and Orthogonal Matrices; Complex Matrices, Inverse and Rank of matrix using elementary transformations, Rank-Nullity theorem; System of linear equations, Characteristic equation, Cayley-Hamilton Theorem and its application, Eigen values and eigenvectors; Diagonalisation of a Matrix, </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_MATHS1">Module 2: Differential Calculus- I
Introduction to limits, continuity and differentiability, Rolle’s Theorem, Lagrange’s Mean value theorem and Cauchy mean value theorem, Successive Differentiation (nth order derivatives), Leibnitz theorem and its application, Envelope, Involutes and Evolutes, Curve tracing: Cartesian and Polar co-ordinates </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_MATHS1">Module 3: Differential Calculus-II
Partial derivatives, Total derivative, Euler’s Theorem for homogeneous functions, Taylor and Maclaurin’s  theorems for a function of one and two variables, Maxima and Minima of functions of several variables, Lagrange Method of Multipliers, Jacobians, Approximation of errors.</string>
    <string name="UNIT4_MATHS1">Module 4: Multivariable Calculus-I
Multiple integration: Double integral, Triple integral, Change of order of integration, Change of variables, Application: Areas and volumes, Center of mass and center of gravity (Constant and variable densities), </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_MATHS1">Module 5: Vector Calculus
Vector differentiation: Gradient, Curl and Divergence and their Physical interpretation, Directional derivatives, Tangent and Normal planes.
Vector Integration: Line integral, Surface integral, Volume integral, Gauss’s Divergence theorem, Green’s theorem, Stoke’s theorem ( without proof) and their applications.
 </string>


    COMMON FIRST YEAR SYLLABUS MATHS2
    <string name="UNIT1_MATHS2">Module 1: Ordinary Differential Equation of Higher Order
        Linear differential equation of nth order with constant coefficients, Simultaneous linear differential equations, Second order linear differential equations with variable coefficients, Solution by changing independent variable, Reduction of order, Normal form, Method of variation of parameters,  Cauchy-Euler equation,  Series solutions (Frobenius Method). </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_MATHS2">Module 2: Multivariable Calculus-II
Improper integrals, Beta and Gama function and their properties, Dirichlet’s integral and its applications, Application of definite integrals to evaluate surface areas and volume of revolutions. </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_MATHS2">Module 3: Sequences and Series
Definition of Sequence and series with examples, Convergence of sequence and series, Tests for convergence of series, (Ratio test, D’ Alembert’s test, Raabe’s test). Fourier series, Half range Fourier  sine and cosine series. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_MATHS2">Module 4: Complex Variable – Differentiation
Limit, Continuity and differentiability, Functions of complex variable, Analytic functions, Cauchy- Riemann equations (Cartesian and Polar form), Harmonic function, Method to find Analytic functions, Conformal mapping, Mobius transformation and their properties </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_MATHS2">Module 5: Complex Variable –Integration
Complex integrals, Contour integrals, Cauchy- Goursat theorem, Cauchy integral formula, Taylor’s series, Laurent’s series, Liouvilles’s theorem, Singularities, Classification of Singularities,  zeros of analytic functions, Residues, Methods of finding residues, Cauchy Residue theorem, Evaluation of real integrals</string>


    COMMON FIRST YEAR SYLLABUS PHYSICS
    <string name="UNIT1_PHYSICS">Module - 1 Relativistic Mechanics:
Frame of reference, Inertial and non-inertial frames, Galilean transformations, MichelsonMorley experiment, Postulates of special theory of relativity, Lorentz transformations, Length contraction, Time dilation, Velocity addition theorem, Variation of mass with velocity, Einstein‟s mass energy relation, Relativistic relation between energy and momentum, Massless particle.  </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_PHYSICS">Module- 2 Electromagnetic Field Theory:
Continuity equation for current density, Displacement current, Modifying equation for the curl of magnetic field to satisfy continuity equation, Maxwell‟s equations in vacuum and in non conducting medium, Energy in an electromagnetic field, Poynting vector and Poynting theorem, Plane electromagnetic waves in vacuum and their transverse nature. Relation between electric and magnetic fields of an electromagnetic wave, Energy and momentum carried by electromagnetic waves, Resultant pressure, Skin depth.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT3_PHYSICS">Module- 3 Quantum Mechanics:
Black body radiation, Stefan‟s law, Wien‟s law, Rayleigh-Jeans law and Planck‟s law, Wave particle duality, Matter waves, Time-dependent and time-independent Schrodinger wave equation, Born interpretation of wave function, Solution to stationary state Schrodinger wave equation for one-Dimensional particle in a box,  Compton effect.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_PHYSICS">Module- 4 Wave Optics:
Coherent sources, Interference in uniform and wedge shaped thin films, Necessity of extended sources, Newton‟s Rings and its applications. Fraunhoffer diffraction at single slit and at double slit, absent spectra, Diffraction grating, Spectra with grating, Dispersive power, Resolving power of grating, Rayleigh‟s criterion of resolution, Resolving power of grating.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_PHYSICS">Module- 5Fibre Optics and Laser:
Fibre Optics: Introduction to fibre optics, Acceptance angle, Numerical aperture, Normalized frequency, Classification of fibre, Attenuation and Dispersion in optical fibres. Laser: Absorption of radiation, Spontaneous and stimulated emission of radiation, Einstein‟s coefficients, Population inversion, Various levels of Laser, Ruby Laser, He-Ne Laser, Laser applications.
 </string>


    COMMON FIRST YEAR SYLLABUS PROGRAMMING
    <string name="UNIT1_PROGRAMMING">Module – 1 : (Introduction to Programming)    ]

Introduction to components of a computer system: Memory, processor, I/O Devices, storage, operating system, Concept of assembler, compiler, interpreter, loader and linker. Idea of Algorithm: Representation of Algorithm, Flowchart, Pseudo code with examples, From algorithms to programs, source code.  Programming Basics: Structure of C program, writing and executing the first C program, Syntax and logical errors in compilation, object and executable code.  Components of C language. Standard I/O in C, Fundamental data types, Variables and memory locations, Storage classes.
 </string>
    <string name="UNIT2_PROGRAMMING">Module – 2 : (Arithmetic expressions and Conditional Branching)
        Arithmetic expressions and precedence:Operators and expression using numeric and relational operators, mixed operands, type conversion, logical operators, bit operations, assignment operator, operator precedence and associativity.
Conditional Branching: Applying if and switch statements, nesting if and else, use of break and default with switch.</string>
    <string name="UNIT3_PROGRAMMING">Module – 3 : (Loops and Functions)
Iteration and loops: use of while, do while and for loops, multiple loop variables, use of break and continue statements. Functions: Introduction, types of functions, functions with array, passing parameters to functions, call by value, call by reference, recursive functions. </string>
    <string name="UNIT4_PROGRAMMING">Module – 4 : (Arrays and Basic Algorithms)
Arrays: Array notation and representation, manipulating array elements, using multi dimensional arrays. Character arrays and strings, Structure, union, enumerated data types, Array of structures, Passing arrays to functions.  Basic Algorithms: Searching and Basic Sorting Algorithms (Bubble, Insertion and Selection), Finding roots of equations, Notion of order of complexity. </string>
    <string name="UNIT5_PROGRAMMING">Module – 5 :( Pointer and File Handling)
Pointers:Introduction, declaration, applications, Introduction to dynamic memory allocation (malloc, calloc, realloc, free), Use of pointers in self-referential structures, notion of linked list (no implementation) </string>
    <string name="title_logo">NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC</string>
    <string name="btn_skip_intro">Skip Intro</string>


    <string name="error_player">There was an error initializing the YouTubePlayer (%1$s)</string>
    <string name="scope">Career in IT is considered one of the most high-paying jobs and is full of opportunities; particularly when India s prowess in information technology industry is recognized across the globe. The pool of talented computer engineers working in IT companies of the USA and Canada shows that IT can take a person to higher levels. Numerous IT companies from India employ huge number of computer professionals in their Indian and overseas offices.</string>

    <string name="STEP">A BTech or BCA/MCA can become an IT engineer. And a person requires +2 with mathematics to pursue BTech or BCA. Others without mathematics too can do various short term certification and diploma courses in various small packages. However, there is a stringent selection procedure at place for computer engineers wherein admission to the BE/ BTech courses is extremely competitive. An internship program at Various IT companies would garner practical knowledge and employability and it is a must and can be either after or during the course.
 </string>
    <string name="start"> Candidates willing to excel in computer engineering should have sound command over mathematics and science to clear entrance exam conducted soon after 12th class. Advanced knowledge of chemistry and physics would help the candidates get through  the entrance exam conducted by engineering colleges in India. Candidates who wish to do BE / BTech in Computer Engineering must have passed 10+2 or equivalent examination, with Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics. Similarly, those who wish to do Diploma in Computer Engineering must have passed 10 + 2 with Science Subjects. Candidates may opt for M.E/ M. Tech in Computer Science for further specialization in Computer Science.
</string>
    <string name="QUESTION">Depending upon the interest the career in IT can be chosen. Those who love programming and coding can do software engineering and those who prefer networking and system administration, can do hardware engineering. IT sector is quite broad in terms of employment and job options. Roles are varieties for Computer engineers in IT sector, but their primary role is to apply the knowledge of mathematics and science to design and develop software to be used by clients or users. There are network engineers, system management professionals besides the computer engineers. Computer software engineers have bright career prospects as the application of software and dependency on it in various walks of life are increasing.
</string>
    <string name="Cost">Studying Information Technology can cost a lot in private engineering colleges. However, government sponsored engineering colleges charge comparatively low. IITs charge from Rs 2,00,000 to Rs 2,70,000, but the fee depends upon the rank of engineering college and reputation. Diploma programs on the other hand cost less and a diploma in computer application can be done at 50,000.
</string>
    <string name="funding">A number of scholarships are available for computer science students. One such scholarship is the Paul Foundation Scholarships and is offered to study BTech and MTech in computer science. Candidates with outstanding academic records are eligible for it.  The NTPC Scholarship for Disabled or Handicapped Engineering Students is also there for students who have some kind of handicap including of visual, hearing or orthopedic.
Students willing to do research in computer science can apply for the Young Engineering Fellowship Program which is offered to students of BTech who are willing to do summer projects conducted by the Indian Institute of Science in Bangalore. Students in third year of any type of engineering degree are applicable for it.
</string>
    <string name="job">Booming IT sector in India has plenty of jobs for fresh computer science graduates. Candidates from top notch engineering colleges however get attractive job offers from MNC IT companies in comparison to not so known engineering colleges. Additionally, candidates with high percentage of mark and good communication skills as well as sound computer knowledge do not face problem in getting a job whether they are from a reputed engineering college or not. Computer engineers can get jobs in non-IT companies like universities, research, private and public industries, government departments, business organisations, commercial organisations and the manufacturing sector, etc.
Besides the Computer Engineers have plenty of options to work in IT companies in departments such as design, development, assembly, manufacture and maintenance, etc. Working as programmer, web developer, and E- commerce specialist with telecommunications companies, automotive companies, aerospace companies, etc. can be a lucrative career option as well. Moreover, numerous national and multi-national computer manufacturing companies, computer hardware system design and development companies, computer networking companies, software development companies, etc. require computer professionals in large numbers.
</string>
    <string name="packet">It is the attraction of higher salaries in IT sector which urges youngsters to opt for a course in computer science. In comparison to other sector, computer science graduates fetch higher salaries from INR 15,000 – 25,000 in the beginning. After gaining +2 years of work experience, they can get a salary of INR 40000. Candidates who get opportunities to work in overseas project get numerous benefits and incentives which may even go to six figures. However, the salary depends a lot upon some factors such as the state of the industry, work experience, qualifications and ability of the candidate, etc. amongst others. Computer Science graduates who are in teaching can fetch a salary of INR 20000 plus dearness allowances and other benefits.
</string>
    <string name="demand">True to its global reputation, the Indian IT sector has lots of scope in terms of growth in employment opportunities. A huge requirement of trained IT engineers is expected in next couple of years. While according to NASSCOM, the Indian IT exports are expected to expand to the tune of US$ 175 billion by 2020 and the domestic sector will account for US$ 50 billion in terms of earnings. Similarly, a huge quantum of profit is expected  from the export and domestic IT sector which would be worth US$ 225 billion.
</string>
    <string name="Market">Widening scope for computer science professionals can be prophesied from the fact that after the recession is over, new jobs would come in large numbers in IT sector. Moreover, with low service cost Indian IT companies have leverage over IT companies in the USA, Canada, and Australia. The low cost Indian IT service attract lot more business even during recession as companies in developed nations try to reduce their production cost and outsource their IT work to Indian IT firms.</string>

    <string name="International">IT sector can truly be considered a global career in terms of its wide scope for professionals. India has been one of the leading exporters of IT talent and Indian computer engineers have played major role in the growth and development of IT sector in the USA, UK, Australia, and Canada. Numbers of employment opportunities are waiting for Indian computer professionals in these countries. Some new avenues too are being opened for Indian computer professionals in Dubai, Singapore, Bangkok, etc. Thanks to global demand for IT services, which is around USD $70 trillion for many new and exciting international careers are opened up for computer professionals.</string>
    <string name="Positives">Despite the fact that recent recession showed the worse days for computer engineers, a great hope still persists for Indian computer science professionals for the reason that India has potential to offer IT services at the fraction of the cost of the USA software developing companies. India has advantage in terms of IT professionals as it produces more in numbers than Western countries; therefore, the demand can be filled only with Indian professionals who are par excellence vis-a-vis computer professionals of the West. Indian IT companies such as Wipro, Infosys, TCS, Patni, HCL, etc. have been able to garner gains even during the recession and have hired a number of computer professionals.
</string>
    <string name="Different">• Software Developers: Software developers are professionals who are concerned with facets of the software development process which involves activities such as design and coding, computer programming, project management, etc.
• Hardware Engineers: These professionals do research, design, develop, test, and oversee the installation of computer hardware which inter alia includes computer chips, circuit boards, systems, modems, keyboards, and printers.
• System Designer: Professionals involved in system designing, Logical and Physical Designing wherein logical designing can be enumerated as the structure and characteristics such as output, input, files, database and procedures, etc.
• System Analyst: Computer engineers who work as systems analyst do research about the existing problems and plan solutions for the problem. They also recommend software and system related problems and coordinate development between business development teams. 
• Networking Engineers: Networking engineers are computer professionals involved in designing, implementation, and troubleshooting of computer networks.
• DBA: DBA or Database Administrator are the professionals who are bestowed with the job to design, implement, maintain, and repair an organization database. Inter alia DBA professionals are also known as Database Coordinator or Database Programmer in IT sector.
</string>
    <string name="Companies">Mechanical engineering is one of the oldest branches of engineering. It is also referred to as the ‘mother’ branch of engineering. Another appealing feature of mechanical engineering is that the application base of this field of study is extremely broad and diverse. Almost all inventions during the ancient period and a vast majority in the modern era are direct contributions of one or the other application of mechanics.
</string>
    <string name="me_intro">Mechanical engineering is one of the oldest branches of engineering. It is also referred to as the ‘mother’ branch of engineering. Another appealing feature of mechanical engineering is that the application base of this field of study is extremely broad and diverse. Almost all inventions during the ancient period and a vast majority in the modern era are direct contributions of one or the other application of mechanics.</string>
    <string name="me_step">Passing 10+2 with PCM (Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics) is the first step you take towards becoming a professional mechanical engineer. To be eligible for a graduate programme (BE/BTech) in a college, you should have scored at least 50% marks and 60% for being eligible for IITs (Indian Institute of Technology) in 10+2 with PCM as subjects. After this, you can sit for various entrance examinations such as: • The Joint Entrance Examination for IITs (IITJEE) for admission to various IITs • All-India Engineering Entrance Exam (AIEEE) for admission to various National Institutes of Technology or regional engineering colleges</string>
    <string name="me_start">To make mechanical engineering your chosen career path, you must have affinity for the way different machines function. This trait can be observed from early childhood when children try to tinker around with different machinery in their immediate vicinity. Such kids often tend to take apart mechanical toys, clocks, bicycles and then they try to assemble them back again. These children are so innovative that they may even try to make new things. Here, parents have a special role to play. They must understand that the child possesses an inquisitive mind that is interested in gaining knowledge about machinery and not in breaking or destroying things. Parents must encourage the child’s curiosity to know more about different gadgets and machines in and around the house. During schooling, the quest to play around with machinery increases all the more. This curiosity often culminates with the child opting for science with the PCM subject combination.</string>
    <string name="me_question">Like other career paths, the entry into this particular branch of engineering also requires you to possess certain basic traits. First and foremost, you must have a penchant for mechanical components and machinery and how these machines work. Then you must be good at physics, chemistry and mathematics. You must also have skills such as an analytical bent of mind, logical reasoning and problem solving. Further, you must have immense patience, physical strength, ability to work for long hours and an inventive spirit that are essential ingredients for becoming a successful mechanical engineer.</string>
    <string name="me_cost">A graduate programme from a private engineering institution will cost you anywhere between Rs.50,000 to Rs.2,00,000 annually. However, in a reputed government run establishment such as the Indian institute of Technology (IIT) or any regional engineering college, you will have to pay an annual fees in the range of anywhere between Rs 30,000 to Rs 40,000.</string>
    <string name="mejob">Educational institutes offering programmes in mechanical engineering generally extend scholarships to students from socially and economically backward classes. For example, IITs waive off the complete tuition fees for students belonging to the socially backward communities. Scholarships, freeships, stipends and financial assistance are also provided to students on the basis of merit and other qualifying criteria.</string>
    <string name="me_scho">Since mechanical engineering is the broadest of all engineering fields, the job prospects on offer for skilled mechanical engineers are aplenty and unending. Mechanical engineers are required to design, test, manufacture, install, operate and maintain a wide array of machines and mechanical systems that are used in countless industries. These professionals can find employment both in the government and private sector undertakings. Major industries that employ mechanical engineers include automobiles, space research, aeronautical, energy and utilities, air conditioning, bio-mechanical industry. Other major employers include giant manufacturing plants, air conditioning and refrigeration industry, turbine manufacturing plants, oil and gas exploration and refining industries and the agricultural sector.</string>
    <string name="me_pay">Mechanical engineering offers a wide variety of career opportunities to job aspirants. The average monthly salary of mechanical engineers who are new to this profession is approximately in the range between Rs.10,000 and Rs.25,000. Good campus placements can fetch even better packages for deserving students. Mechanical engineers who hold a post-graduate degree from a reputed academic institute tend to get better offers than diploma and degree holders. From here on the annual pay packet depends on a number of factors such as the skill set possessed, experience, expertise, the employer, nature of roles and responsibilities, etc. Highly skilled mechanical engineers can easily command pay packets as high as Rs 40-45 lacs per annum.</string>
    <string name="me_demand">There is great demand for skilled mechanical engineers in different segments of the industry. Their expertise is required in traditional manufacturing industries such as automobiles, aviation, shipping, aerospace, power plants and machinery manufacturing. In recent times, the services of expert mechanical engineers have even been sought in fields such as nanotechnology, biomedical engineering, energy conservation and environmental engineering. There is also great requirement for mechanical engineer consultants who have management skills along with technical proficiency. The primary role of such professionals is to manage both technology and people and firms that provide engineering consultancy require them. Various engineering colleges and polytechnics across the country are doing their best to meet the burgeoning demand of skilled mechanical engineering professionals.</string>
    <string name="me_marcket">The job market for mechanical engineers is perennial. Even the vagaries of the global economic crisis could not knock out the demand for these professionals in the Indian job market. Although some branches of mechanical engineering went out of focus during the meltdown period, the overall situation was much better as compared with other careers. On the brighter side, things are getting back to normal and this evergreen career path is again gaining coin amongst career aspirants as it did during the pre-meltdown years. In fact, this is a period of resurgence for mechanical engineers. They not only have countless options in the industrial sector but they can also make foray into new realms of technology and even get into management and technical consultancy. According to a survey, mechanical engineering is amongst the most sought after branches of engineering preferred by students seeking admission to various technical institutes across India in the recent years.</string>
    <string name="me_focus">Highly qualified professionals from this field, such as post-graduates from various IITs, often seek suitable employment in foreign countries. It is not that only highly qualified mechanical engineers get opportunity to work abroad. If you are employed in a multinational company, you may also get the chance to work on offshore projects</string>


</resources>
